Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鳥字幕合併器SubindexV0.5
Created time 13.03.14 11:36:02
翻譯：米粒@douban/TLF 交流分享 請勿商用 保護版權 人人有責
導演：昆汀·塔倫蒂諾
傑米·福克斯
克奡策咱情P瓦爾茲
萊昂納多·迪卡普媔
凱莉·華盛頓
薩繆爾·L·傑克遜
被解放的姜戈
DJANGO UNCHAINED Caption and sync: jcdr
1858年，美國內戰之前兩年
德克薩斯州某處
是誰在黑暗堸降陌幸帚滿H
Who's that stumblin' around in the dark?
報上名來，否則等著吃槍子兒吧！
State your business, or prepare to get winged!
先生們，冷靜點，我不是壞人
Calm yourselves gentlemen, I mean you no harm.
我也只是個疲勞的旅者
I'm simply a fellow weary traveler.
真冷啊，晚上好先生們，
Good cold evening gentlemen,
我正在找兩個奴隸販子
I'm looking for a pair of slave traders
他們叫斯派克兄弟
that go by the name of the Speck Brothers.
是不是就是你們？
Might that be you?
是誰問的？
Who wants to know?
是我
Well, I do.
我是金·舒爾茲醫生， 這是我的馬，弗堹
I'm Dr. King Schultz, this is my horse, Fritz.
什麼醫生啊？
What kinda doctor?
牙醫
Dentist.
你們是不是就是斯派克兄弟，
Now are you the Speck Brothers,
這些奴隸是不是你們 在格林威爾奴隸拍賣會上買來的？
and did you purchase those men at the Greenville slave auction?
是又怎樣？
So what?
我只是想跟你們@#¥¥%（這埵陪茧不是英語）
So, I wish to parley with you.
說英語！
Speak English.
噢對不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
請原諒，那是我的一門外語
Please forgive me, it is a second language.
在你的商品清單堶情A我...
Now, amongst your inventory, I've been led to believe,
認為有一個人我很想買
is a specimen I'm keen to acquire.
你們好哇，可憐人
Hello you poor devils!
你們之中是不是有一個， 以前在卡拉坎農場呆過？
Is there one amongst you, who was formerly a resident of The Carrucan Plantation?
我是從卡拉坎農場來的
I'm from The Carrucan Plantation.
剛才是誰？
Who said that?
你叫什麼名字？
What's your name?
姜戈
Django.
你就是我要找的人了
Then you're exactly the one I'm looking for.
你知道布埵咱S弟是誰嗎？
Do you know who the Brittle Brothers are?
都有誰？
Who are they?
大約翰…
Big John…
埃利斯...
Ellis…
還有拉什， 他們有時候叫他小拉什的
and Raja… sometime they call him Lit'le Raj.
他們之前是卡拉坎農場的監工
They was overseers at Carrucan plantation.
現在不在了
Not anymore.
告訴我…
Tell me…
如果你能再見到這三兄弟， 你能認出來嗎？
If you were to see any of these three gentlemen again, would you recognize them?
嘿!
Hey!
別那樣跟他說話
Stop talk with 'em like that.
哪樣啊？
Like what?
剛才那樣!
Like that!
好兄弟，我只是¥%…@#
My good man, I'm simply trying to ascertain-
該死的，說英語
Speak English, goddammit!
大家都冷靜點嘛,
Everybody calm down,
我只是個想好好買東西的顧客而已
I'm simply a customer trying to conduct a transaction.
我不管，不賣了，
I don't care. No sale.
你走吧！
Now off wit' you!
別這樣，他們當然是拿來賣的啦
Oh, don't be ridiculous, o'course they're for sale.
老實走開！
Move it.
天哪，你這是舉著槍嚇唬我呢，
My good man, did you simply get carried away with your dramatic gesture,
還是非得殺了我不可啊
or are you pointing your weapon at me with lethal intention?
最後一次機會了，滑頭
Last chance, fancy pants.
那好吧
Oh, very well…
不好意思連你的座駕也一起傷了，
I'm sorry to have put a bullet in your beast,
我只是不想讓你在冷靜下來之前
but I didn't want you to do anything rash
輕舉妄動什麼的
before you had a moment to come to your senses.
你這該死的狗娘養的!
Goddamn son of a bitch!
你打傷了我的馬！
You shot Roscoe!
還殺了我哥！
And you killed Ace!
是他威脅要殺了我， 我才殺了他的
Hey, I only shot your brother once he threatened to shoot me.
我想我應該有...
And I do believe I have
一，二，三，四，五...五個目擊證人支持我呢
one, two, three, four, five witnesses who can attest to that fact.
把我的腿都打爆了！
Damn legs busted!
那是毫無疑問了。 現在你可以試著盡量叫得小點聲
No doubt. Now, if you can keep your caterwauling down to a minimum,
我對小姜戈還有問題沒問完呢
I'd like to finish my line of inquiry with young Django.
啊——啊——操你媽哦該死的...
God fucking dammit!
剛才說到，
As I was saying,
如果你再見到布埵咱S弟， 能認出來嗎？
if you were to see the Brittle Brothers again, you could recognize them?
可以
Yeah.
成交！斯派克先生，
Sold American! So Mr. Speck,
姜戈你開價多少？
Mr. Speck, how much for young Django here?
這樁生意估計會很棘手啊
That iron is nasty business.
幫我拿一下這個好嗎？
Could you hold this for a moment?
謝謝 姜戈，你騎那匹馬
Thank you. Django, get up on that horse.
還有如果我是你的話， 我會去拿那位去世了的斯派克老兄的大衣穿上
Also if I were you, I'd take that winter coat the dear departed Speck left behind.
黑鬼，你膽敢碰我哥哥的大衣
Nigger, don't you touch my brother's coat!
啊——！該死！
Goddammit!
這堿O一百...十...
One hundred… ten…
二十五塊
twenty… and five…
買姜戈的
for young Django here.
而且你哥也不在了，既然用不著， 我就連他的馬也一起買了吧
And since you won't be needing it anymore, I'd like to purchase your brother's nag.
哦還有，斯派克先生， 我需要你給我開個發票
Also… Mr. Speck, I am afraid I will require a bill of sale.
你有嗎？
Do you have one?
去死吧，死牙醫！
You go to hell, dentist!
我想也沒有
I thought not.
別著急!
No worries!
我有備而來
I come prepared.
謝謝
Thank you.
這文書就跟發票效果一樣了
This will serve nicely as a bill of sale.
現在你們這些可憐人呢
Now as to you poor devils…
我覺得，既然你們需要考慮下一步該怎麼辦
So as I see it, when it comes to the subject of what to do next,
你們現在有兩個選擇
you gentlemen have two choices.
一，我走了以後， 你們把馬從斯派克身上搬走，
One: once I'm gone, you could lift that beast off the remaining Speck,
把他抬到最近的鎮上去
then carry him to the nearest town.
也就是最少有37英里，從你們來的地方到這兒
Which would be at least thirty-seven miles back the way you came.
或者，二，
Or Two:
你們把鎖鏈解開，
You could unshackle yourselves…
拿上那把槍，給他腦袋來一發 把他倆埋了，
take that rifle, put a bullet in his head, bury the two of them deep,
然後找一個更開明自由的地方去吧
and then make your way to a more enlightened area of this country.
選擇權在你們手上
The choice is yours.
哦還有， 你們中間是天文愛好者的應該不多吧
Oh, and on the off chance there are any astronomy aficionados amongst you,
北極星是那邊那個
the North Star is that one.
拜拜咯
Tata.
兄弟們等等，我們可以談談
Now wait a minute fellas, let's talk about this.
這種情況下你們更要講道理啊
You gotta be reasonable on a situation like this.
我又不是壞人，我只是做我本職
I'm not a bad guy, look I'm just doing my job!
我最後一個蘋果不是還給你吃了嗎？
Blueberry, didn't I give you my last apple?
這麼跟你們說吧， 把我帶去埃爾帕索鎮上，你們就自由了
Tell you what boys, take me to Lit'le Duck in El Paso, I'll get you your freedom.
不，不
No. No, please-
德州多特
現在，這個藥晚上吃兩片， 然後到了白天...
騎在馬上的那個是黑人？
大家幹嘛都盯著看？
What's everybody staring at?
他們從沒見過黑人騎馬
They never seen a nigger on a horse before.
店老闆早上好
Good morning inn keeper!
兩位疲勞的旅客想來杯啤酒
Two beers for two weary travelers.
現在還太早了
Ah, it's still a bit early.
我們還要一個小時才開門
We won't be open for another hour.
到時候我們會提供早餐的
By then we'll be servin' breakfast.
喂，喂，喂！
Wow wow wow wow!
你在幹嘛呢老兄，
What the hell you think you doin', boy?
把那黑鬼轟出去
Get that nigger outta here.
救命啊！救命！
Help! Help!
店老闆！
Inn keeper!
記得去叫治安官，別叫警長啊
Remember, get the sheriff, not the marshall.
Alas…
看來我們只能自己給自己當酒保了
Now we must act as our own bartender.
坐下吧孩子
Sit down, my boy.
你是哪種牙醫啊？
What kinda dentist are you?
先不談那馬車吧， 我已經有五年沒有干牙醫的活兒了
Despite that cart, I haven't practiced dentistry in five years.
最近呢我開發了新的職業...
These days I practice a new profession.
賞金獵手
Bounty Hunter.
知道什麼是賞金獵手嗎？
D'you know what a Bounty Hunter is?
不知道
No.
Well…
奴隸交易是用錢買活人對吧，
The way the slave trade deals in human lives for cash,
賞金獵手就是用錢買死人的
a bounty hunter deals in corpses.
Prost.
僱主會給某人的腦袋懸賞，
The state places a bounty on a man's head,
我就去追蹤，找到並且殺了那個人
I track that man, I find that man, I kill that man,
殺了他之後我就把他的屍體送回僱主
after I've killed him, I transport that man's corpse back to the authorities,
現在說說還挺容易似的哈
and sometimes that's easier said then done,
我給他們看到屍體，證明， 我確實是
I show that corpse to the authorities proving, yes indeed,
殺了這個人,然後呢， 僱主就可以給我賞金了
I truly have killed him, at which point the authorities pay me the bounty.
跟奴隸買賣一樣，都是拿錢買人
So… like slavery, it's a flesh-for-cash business.
賞金是什麼？
What's a bounty?
就像獎品
It's like a reward.
你殺了人，別人還給你獎品？
You kill people and they give you a reward?
某些人是這樣的
Certain people, yeah.
壞人？
Bad people?
人越壞，獎品就越大
Aah!
Badder they are, bigger the reward!
所以我才找到了你，
Which brings me to you.
不過我必須承認現在的情況我還是有點困惑的
And I must admit that I'm at a bit of a quandary when it comes to you.
一方面，我鄙視奴隸制。
On one hand, I despise slavery.
但另一方面呢，
On the other hand…
我需要你的幫忙，所以假如不給你拒絕的權利， 那就再好不過了
I need your help, if you're not in a position to refuse, all the better.
所以現在我只能 用這奴隸制給我幫幫忙了
So for the time being, I'm gonna make this slave malarkey work to my benefit.
當然...我也說了，
Still… having said that…
我很有負罪感
I feel guilty.
所以...
So…
我需要我們達成個協議
I would like the two of us to enter into an agreement.
我在找布埵咫T兄弟
I'm looking for the Brittle Brothers.
但這次我略微有點劣勢
However I've had this endeavor, I'm- I'm at a slight disadvantage,
目前為止，我都不知道他們長什麼樣
in so far as, I don't know what they look like.
但是你知道。對吧？
But you do… don't you?
我很清楚他們的長相
I know what they look like, all right.
好
Good.
現在約定是這樣，
So here's my agreement.
你跟著我一路走，直到我們找到他們
You travel with me until we find them-
朝哪堥哄H
Where we goin'?
我聽說他們至少有兩個在蓋丁堡， 但不知道具體位置
I hear at least two of them are overseeing up in Gatlinburg, but I don't know where.
也就是說我們要走訪蓋丁堡的每個農場 直到找到他們
That means we visit every plantation in Gatlinburg till we find them.
等找到以後，
And when we find them…
你指出他們，我來殺了他們
you point them out, and I kill them!
只要做到，我同意給你自由，
You do that, I agree to give you your freedom,
還有每個人頭25美元...也就是一共75...
twenty-five dollars per Brittle brother -that's seventy-five dollars,
說時遲啊那時快，治安官來了
and as if on cue, here comes the sheriff.
好了，歡樂的時光結束了
Okay boys, fun's over.
出來吧
Come on out.
好了大傢伙兒，冷靜
All right folks, calm down.
回去做自己的事吧
You bout your business.
這倆人馬上就滾蛋了
The jokers will be gone soon.
我得問問…
Now…
你們幹嘛來我的鎮上找麻煩，
why y'all wanna come into my town and start trouble,
把這些良民都給嚇壞了
and… scare all these nice people?
就沒別的事情可做了嗎，
You ain't got nothin' better to do,
敢來我比爾·夏普的鎮上，到處撒野！！
than to come into Bill Sharp's town and show your ass?
你都對我們治安官做了什麼？
What did you jus' do to our sheriff?
現在你可以去喊警長來了
Now you can get the marshall.
警長，警長！
Marshall, marshall!
我們堶接尼a?
Should we wait inside?
我們能不能走？
Can't we just leave?
你先請
After you.
把那塊板移開，移到馬路對面車那堨h
Move that buckboard long ways 'cross the street from the saloon!
我要六個人，拿好槍
I want six men, six riffles behind it.
兩個人拿槍在這個屋頂，
I want two men, two rifles up on this roof,
兩個在那個屋頂
two men two rifles on that roof.
槍桿全部對準前門
All the barrels aimed at that front door.
還有誰，把可憐的比爾從街上拖走啊
Somebody git poor Bill outta the goddamn street.
堶悸漱H！
You in the saloon!
門外已經佈滿了來復槍
We got a hundred riffles aimed on every way outta that buildin'!
只有一個活著出來的機會
You got once chance git outta this alive!
你和你的黑鬼給我馬上出來，手舉在頭頂，
You and your nigger come out right now with your hands over your head,
我是說，現在馬上！
and I mean, right now!
我是否有這個榮幸現在正跟警長對話？
Is this the marshall I have the pleasure of addressing?
是我
Yes it is.
我是美利堅警長吉爾·塔圖姆
This is U.S. Marshall Gill Tatum.
好極了！警長先生，
That wunderbar, marshall.
我已經放下了全部武器
I have relieved myself of all weapons,
而且如你指示的，
and just as you have instructed,
我正準備出來了
I am ready to step outside,
手也放到頭頂
with my hands raised above my head.
我相信你，
I trust,
作為美國司法部門的代表，
as a representative of the criminal justice system of The United States of America,
是不會活活打死我的
I shan't be shot down in the street,
不管是你還是你的手下
by either you or your deputies,
在我被法庭審判之前
before I've had my day in court.
你是說你剛才對治安官做的這一切？
You mean like you did our sheriff?
像打狗一樣打死了他！
Shot 'em down like a dog in the street!
我就是這個意思！
Yes, that's exactly what I mean!
我有沒有你法律上的保證，
Do I have your word as a lawman,
不會把我像狗一樣打死？
not to shoot me down like a dog in the street?
雖然那樣我們都會很喜聞樂見
Well, as much as we'd all enjoy seein' somethin' like that,
但我們鎮上沒人會騙你這種劊子手！
ain't nobody gonna cheat the hangman in my town.
好的，那我們出來了
Fair enough marshall, here we come!
外面那幫人有點緊張過頭，
They're a little tense out there.
所以你別亂動，讓我來說話
So don't make any quick movements, and let me do the talking.
過來
Come ahead.
你沒拿槍吧？
You unarmed?
沒有
Yes indeed we are.
塔圖姆警長，你，還有你的手下，
Marshall Tatum, may I address you and your deputies,
以及顯然整個多特娷穖ㄕb了，
and apparently the entire town of Daughtrey,
請允許我說明一下剛才的事
as to the incident that just occurred?
說
Go on.
我是金·舒爾茲醫生，
My name is Dr. King Schultz,
跟警長你一樣， 我也是為法庭做事的人
and like yourself, marshall, I am a servant of the court.
剛才倒地身亡的那個人，
The man lying dead in the dirt,
多特娷磲漫~民把他選為治安官的，
who the good people of Daughtrey saw fit to elect as their sheriff,
他自稱是比爾·夏普，
who went by the name of Bill Sharp,
但其實是一個在通緝的逃犯，叫威勒·派克
is actually a wanted outlaw by the name of Willard Peck,
他的人頭值兩百塊
with a price on his head of two hundred dollars.
是死是活可都是兩百塊
Now, that's two hundred dollars, dead or alive.
一派胡言！
The hell you say!
我也知道這個消息會讓人很不安
I'm aware this is probably disconcerting news.
但我打賭這個人是過去兩年內
But I'm willing to wager this man was elected sheriff
才被選為治安官的
sometime in the last two years.
我知道這個，是因為三年前，
I know this because three years ago,
他還在德州盧伯克的克堮睅i牛場給牛刷毛
he was rustling cattle from the B.C. Corrigan Cattle Company of Lubbock, Texas.
我這埵酗@封
Now this is a warrant,
德州奧斯丁的 巡迴法庭法官亨利·阿倫·勞德米克簽的逮捕令
made out by circuit court Judge Henry Allen Laudermilk of Austin Texas.
你可以給他發電報
You're encouraged to wire him.
他會說明我的身份
He'll back up who I am,
以及你們親愛的治安官過去叫啥
and who your dear departed sheriff was.
換句話說呢警長，
In other words marshall,
你還欠我兩百塊呢
you owe me two hundred dollars.
沃槽...
I'll be damned.
等布埵咱S弟這單活兒做完，
After this Brittle business is behind us…
你就恢復自由身了，
you'll be a free man.
還有一匹馬， 身上還有75塊錢
With a horse, seventy five dollars in your back pocket.
接下來有什麼打算
What's your plan after that?
我要找到我老婆…
Find my wife…
買回她的自由身
and buy her freedom.
姜戈
Django…
我都不知道你已經結婚了
I had no idea you were a married man.
奴隸們也相信婚姻？
Do most slaves believe in marriage?
我和我老婆相信
Me and my wife do.
卡拉坎農場的人都相信，所以我們才…
All men in Carrucan did, and that's why we uh…
才逃走的
we run off.
姜戈…
Django…
姜戈，姜戈
Django, Django…
你態度很硬啊，姜戈
You got sand, Django.
年輕人都這樣
Boy's got sand.
但一個態度這麼硬的奴隸我不能要
I got no use for niggers with sand.
你給他在臉上燙個「R」，說明他逃跑過
I want you to burn the runaway “r” right here on his cheek.
那女的也是
And the girl too.
你們把他們帶去格林威爾拍賣會
And I want you to take 'em to the Greenville auction,
把他賣了…
and sell 'em…
他們倆
Both of 'em…
分開賣
Separately.
這個呢...
And this one…
賣個便宜價
you will sell him cheap.
在格林威爾...
In Greenville?
總會有個銷售記錄辦公室之類的
There should be some sort of a records office.
你知道她賣出的時間
You know when she was sold…
你也知道她是哪堥茠
you know where she came from…
你也有她的名字...
and you know her name.
她叫什麼名字？
What is her name?
布隆希達
Broomhilda.
什麼？
What?
布隆希達
Broom-hilda.
- 布隆希達？ - 嗯
– Broomhilda? – Hm-hm.
她以前的農場主是德國人嗎？
Were her owners German?
是啊，你怎麼知道？
Yeah, how you know?
她不是卡拉坎農場出生的， 以前是由一位德國太太撫養的
She wan't born on The Carrucan Plantation, she was raised by a German mistress.
姓范·夏夫特
Von Shafts.
她也能說一點德語
She speak a little German too.
- 你老婆？ - 是啊
– Your wife? – Hm-hm.
她小時候，太太教了她一些所以她能和周圍人說話
When she was little, her mistress taught her so she has somebody speak German with.
所以讓我總結一下啊，
Alright, let me get this straight.
你的老婆是奴隸，她說德語， 名字還叫布隆希達·范·夏夫特？
Your slave wife speaks German, and her name is Broomhilda Von Shaft?
正是
Yep.
他們都叫我希爾蒂
They call me Hildi.
田納西州
等到了這些農場，
When we gain access to these plantations,
我們就要像是演戲一樣了
we'll be putting on an “Act”.
你會扮演一個角色
You'll  be playing a character.
嗯？
Hm?
不行？
No?
在演戲過程中， 你永遠不能打破角色做以外的事
But during the act, you can never break character.
明白了？
D'you understand?
不能打破角色，嗯
Yeah. Don't break character.
你的角色呢就是「侍從」
And you character is that of the “Valet”.
啥玩意
What that is?
就是奴僕，說得好聽點而已
That's a fancy word for servant.
－ 「侍從」 － 嗯
– “Valet”. – Hm-hm!
姜戈，你現在可以為自己的角色選戲服了
And now Django, you may chose your character's costume.
我可以自己選自己的衣服了？
You want that I pick up my own clothes?
當然！
You- but of course!
黑人在這塊地方騎馬可是違法的
It's against the law for niggers to ride horses in this territory.
這是我的侍從，我的侍從不走路的
This is my valet, my valet does not walk.
我說了，黑人騎馬...
I said niggers on horses-
他叫姜戈，是自由身，想騎什麼就騎什麼
His name is Django, he's a free man, he can ride what he pleases.
在我農場就不行
Not on my property.
我的黑奴在，就不行
Not around my niggers he can't.
這位先生
My good sir…
可能我們一開始沒說清楚
perhaps we got off on the wrong boot.
讓我重新介紹一下。
Allow me to unring this bell.
我是金·舒爾茲醫生， 這是我的侍從，姜戈
My name is Dr. King Schultz, this is my valet Django,
這是我們的馬，托尼和弗堹
and these are our horses Tony and Fritz.
本內特先生,
Mr. Bennett,
我知道您是一位紳士，也是一位商人
I've been lead to believe that you are a gentleman, and a business man.
我們才從德州 一路駕車來到田納西，
And it is for these attributes we've ridden from Texas
跟您見面
to Tennessee to parley with you now.
我想要從您這媔R一位黑奴
I wish to purchase one of your nigger gals.
你和你的狗腿從德州跑來田納西， 來買我的奴隸
You and your Jimmie rode from Texas to Tennessee, to buy one of my nigger gals?
也不打個招呼？不是開玩笑吧
No appointment, no nuttin'?
我想就是這樣
Oh, I'm afraid so.
如果我說，我不喜歡你， 也不喜歡你這打扮奇怪的黑鬼
Well what if I had to say I don't like you, or your fancy pants nigger,
我一塊破銅爛鐵都不會賣給你
and I wouldn't sell you a tinkers damn.
你有什麼想說的嗎？
Now what'cha gotta say about that?
本內特先生,
Mr. Bennett,
如果你真是一位商人 且如我聽說的那樣，
if you are the business man I've been led to believe you to be,
我這埵酗迨d個理由，可以讓你改變主意
I have five thousand things, I might say, that could change your mind.
快進來，給你們拿點冷飲
Well com'on inside, and get yourself somethin' cool to drink.
– Huh? – Hm-hm.
或許我們談生意的時候呢，
Oh maybe, while we discuss business,
你可以讓你親愛的黑人家僕
you could provide one of your loveliest black creatures
給姜戈展示展示這了不起的莊園
to escort Django here around your magnificent grounds.
沒問題，貝蒂娜！
Oh, absolutely! Eh, Betina!
我在，大老爹？
Yessir, Big Daddy?
你的跟班叫什麼名字來著？
Eh… What's your Jimmie name again?
姜戈
– Django. – Django.
貝蒂娜，帶姜戈到處逛逛，
Betina sugar, could you take Django there,
給他看看這了不起的農場
and take him around the grounds here to show him all the pretty stuff.
聽您吩咐，大老爹
As you please, Big Daddy.
貝尼特先生，
Oh, Mr. Bennett,
我必須提醒一下 姜戈是自由身，他不能被像奴隸一樣對待
I must remind you Django is a free man. He cannot be treated like a slave.
在允許的範圍之內，他必須得到像我一樣的待遇
Within the bounds of good taste, he must be treated as an extension of myself.
明白了，舒爾茲，貝蒂娜聽到了？
Understood, Schultz. Betina, sugar?
是的
Yes, sir?
姜戈不是奴隸
Django isn't a slave.
姜戈是自由身，明白了？
Django is a free man. You understand?
你不能像待其他黑鬼一樣待他，
You can't treat him like any of these other niggers around here,
因為他不是其他黑鬼，明白了？
cause he ain't like any of these other niggers around here. Ya got it?
你要我像對待白人一樣待他？
You wan' I should treat him like white folks?
不，
No.
我沒這麼說
That's not what I said.
那我就不知道怎麼做了，大老爹
Then I don't know what'cha want, Big Daddy.
能看出來
Yes… I can see that.
Uh…
那個從鎮上來的修玻璃窗的小子叫什麼？
What's the name of that peckawood boy from town that works with the glass?
他媽媽在木材廠工作的？
His mama works at the lumber yard.
噢，你是說傑瑞
Oh, you mean Jerry.
對，那個小孩叫傑瑞
That's the boy's name, Jerry!
你知道傑瑞吧？
You know Jerry, don't you sugar?
是的，大老爹
Yes 'em, Big Daddy.
那就是了，
Well that's it then…
就像對待傑瑞一樣對待他
You just treat 'em like you would Jerry.
我們剛才從「大宅」那媢L來
The house we just left from, is the big house.
大老爹這樣叫的，因為那房子是很大
Big daddy call it that, cause it's big.
那個是儲藏室
That there is the pantry.
大老爹把平時吃的肉都放在那
That's where Bid Daddy hang out his day meat.
堶悼是松鼠
Full o'squirrels.
你是為你主人做什麼的？
What'cha do for your massa'?
沒聽到他說嗎，我不是奴隸？
Didn't you hear him tell ya I ain't no slave?
所以你是真的自由了？
So you really free?
就是這樣
Yes. I as free.
那你是說，是你自己想要穿成這樣的？
You mean you wanna dress like that?
貝蒂娜，我有事情要問你
Betina, I need to ask you something.
什麼事？
What'cho want?
我在找三個白人，男的
I'm lookin' for three white men.
三兄弟，做監工的 姓布埵囿滿A你認識嗎？
Three brothers, overseers. Their name is Brittle. Do you know 'em?
布埵?
Brittle?
是的，布埵 約翰，埃利斯，
Yes, Brittle. John Brittle, Ellis Brittle,
還有羅傑，有時候被叫做小拉什的
Roger Brittle. Sometime called Li'le Raj.
我不認識他們
I don't know dem.
他們可能改了別的名字
They could be usin' a different name.
他們這過去一年有可能來過這個農場
They would have come to the plantation this past year.
你是說夏弗兄弟？
You mean The Shaffers?
有可能。是三兄弟嗎？
Maybe. Three brother?
嗯
Ah-huh.
－ 他們在這？ － 嗯
– Are they here? – Ah-huh.
能給我指出來嗎？
Could you point one of 'em out to me?
一個在那邊地
Well one's over in that field.
如果老卡拉坎還在， 是不會喜歡你這樣做的…
Old man Carrucan ain't going to appreciate this now, she- she-
她是在屋子堶掠筐う滿A約翰， 你這樣會把她的皮膚都毀了
she work in a house, John, you could mess her skin up,
要是毀了，她就…
and you gonna mess it up, she ain't gonna be worth no-
就一文不值了
she ain't gonna worth a damn thing.
就像聖經說的...
Like- like the bible say…
聽著，我告訴你了，是我逼她這樣做的
Look, I- I told you, I was the one to make her do it.
準備好了？
You're ready?
她是跟著我才這樣的， 現在被鞭子打的人，
She the one who went up for me and, thing about you we gettin' whipped now,
應該是我！應該是我啊約翰， 我在這兒時間夠長了，你也知道我的！
that should be me! That should be me John, I been here long enough, you know me!
你認識我很久了！
You know me a long time, now!
你也知道卡拉坎主人是不會同意這麼做的！
You know master Carrugen ain't gonna appreciate this!
她是…她是家僕！
She's- she's a house slave!
?7?8尋找自由
?Looking for freedom
?Looking for freedom ah-aah
求，求你了
Please, please now.
如果這就是你想要的，讓我可憐兮兮地求饒...
If this what you want, to keep me funny fighting for each other, please…
我喜歡你求饒的樣子
I like the way you beg, boy.
是你要找的人嗎？
Is that who you was lookin' for?
正是
Yep.
另外兩個呢？
Where the other two of 'em?
他們在馬廄那堙A小朱迪剛才打碎了雞蛋， 他們正在懲罰她
They by the stable, punishin' Little Jody for breakin' eggs.
他們在打小朱迪？
They whippin' Little Jody?
給我指一下那個方向
Point me in that direction.
走到那棵樹，一直走
You go to that tree, and keep goin' that way.
把那個跟我一起來的男人叫來
Go git that white man I came here with.
來吧，來吧朱迪！
Com'on now. Com'on, Jody!
讓我...把你安頓安頓
Let me all… get you set up!
主說，害怕...
And the Lord said the fear of ye…
和恐懼...
and the dread of ye…
是屬於每個人的
shall be on every beast of here.
嘿，給我，把手給我
Hey, gimme that of what? You better gimme that arm,
把手給我！
you gotta gimme that arm!
好了她準備好了！
Okay, she ready!
完事兒之後，瞧瞧你敢不敢再打碎雞蛋了
And after this, we'll see if you break eggs again.
約翰·布埵哄I
John Brittle!
記得我嗎？
Remember me?
我喜歡你去死的樣子！
I like the way you die, boy!
該死的狗娘養的！
Goddamn son-of-a-bitch!
你們還想繼續看吧？
Ya'all wanna see somethin'?
噢不！
Ooh no!
他們是誰？
Who are they?
這個是大約翰，那個是小拉什
That's Big John, and that's little Raj.
埃利斯呢？
Where's Ellis?
就那邊田里正在拚命逃跑的那個
He's the one hightailin' it across that field right now.
－ 你確定那個是他？ － 嗯
– You sure that's him? – Yeah.
－ 毫無疑問嗎？ － 我也不知道
– Positive? – I dunno.
－ 你不知道自己肯不肯定？ － 「毫無疑問」是什麼意思我不知道
– You don't know if you're positive? – I don't know what positive means.
就是說你打包票
It means you're sure.
－ 是 － 是什麼？
– Yes. – Yes, what?
是我肯定那個是埃利斯·布埵
Yes I'm sure it is Ellis Brittle.
「毫無疑問」他已經死了
I'm positive he dead.
姜戈！
Django!
大家冷靜
Everybody calm down,
我們不會傷害其他任何人
we mean no one else any harm.
你們倆到底是誰？
Who are you two jokers?
我是金·舒爾茲醫生，
I am Dr. King Schultz, a legal representative
是美國犯罪法庭的執行代表，
of the criminal justice system of the United States of America,
左邊這位是自由人姜戈，我的副手
the man to my left is Django Freeman, he's my deputy.
我的口袋埵雀e捕令
In my pocket is a warrant
德州奧斯汀的法官 亨利·阿倫·勞德米克簽署的
signed by circuit court judge Henry Allen Laudermilk of Austin Texas,
不管死活，都需要逮捕以下三人，
for the arrest and capture, dead or alive, of
約翰·布埵哄A羅傑·布埵哄A 還有埃利斯·布埵
John Brittle, Roger Brittle, and Ellis Brittle.
他們姓夏弗
They've gone by the name Shaffer.
那是你們聽說他們叫夏弗， 這幾個屠夫真名叫布埵
You know them by the name of Shaffer, but the butchers real name was Brittle.
他們都是通緝犯，法律要置他們死地
These are wanted men. The law wants them for murder.
再重申一遍，逮捕令說了，不管死活
Now I reiterate, the warrant states dead or alive,
所以我的副手和我剛才殺了他們
so when Mr. Freeman and myself executed these men on sight,
是在法律規定的範圍內的
we were operating within our legal boundaries.
我認識到…
I realize…
你們很激動
passions are high,
但我必須警告你們
but I must warn you,
威脅恐嚇法庭官員是會被懲罰的
the penalty for taking deadly force against a office of the court
尤其在他執行任務的時候
in the performance of his duty is,
你們會被活活吊死哦
you will be hung by the neck until you're dead.
需要我從口袋堮野X逮捕令來給你看看嗎？
May I please remove the warrant from my pocket so you may examine it?
給我
Gimmie.
滿意了？
Satisfied?
我能拿回來了吧？
May I have that back, please?
滾出我的地盤
Get off my land.
馬上馬上
Post haste.
快點把屍體裝起來
Load up the bodies as quickly as you can,
我們趕緊走吧
and let's get out of here.
該死的
Hell…
就是他們這兩個狗娘養的
That's 'em sonsabitches.
除非他們先動手，我們不能開槍
Now unless they start shootin' first… nobody shoot 'em.
對付這倆人再簡單不過了吧
That's way too simple for these jokers.
我們要把那個跟黑鬼在一起的傢伙抽死
We're gonna whip that nigger lover to death.
我本人要親自把他抽筋扒皮
And I'm gonna personally strip and clip that garboon myself.
該死…
Damn…
我戴著這個屁都看不見啊
I can't see fuckin' shit outta this thing.
我們到底準備好了沒啊
We ready, or what?
等等，我屁都看不見啊
Ah hold on, I'm fuckin' with my eye holes.
該死
Oh shit.
弄得更糟糕了
I just made it worse.
這貨到底誰做的啊？
Who made this goddamn shit?
威勒的老婆
Willard's wife.
那他媽的自己做面罩啊！
W?ll m?k? y?u ?wn g?dd?mn m??k?!
沒人說他們不感謝詹妮做的面罩啊
Look, nobody's sayin' they don't appreciate what Jenny did.
如果只是需要在袋子上割個洞，
Well if all I hadda do was cut a hole in a bag,
我應該能弄得比這好吧
I coulda cut it better than this.
羅伯特？你能看到嗎？
How 'bout you Robert, can you see?
看不太清楚
Not too good.
我是說，如果我保持頭不動，那還能看清
I mean, if I don't move my head, I can see pretty good, more or less.
但如果開始騎馬，這個袋子就亂動， 我就只能盲騎了
But when I start ridin', the bag's moving all over, and I'm ridin' blind.
該死！
Oh shit!
我把我的也弄壞了
I just made mine worse.
有誰帶了備用的嗎？
Anybody bring any extra bags?
沒人會帶備用的！
No, nobody brought an extra bag!
只是問問而已啊
I'm just asking.
騎馬的時候也必須戴著嗎？
Do we hafta wear 'em when we ride?
你們都在想什麼呢？
Oh well Shitfire!
如果騎馬的時候不戴面罩， 那我們的初衷是什麼啊？
If you don't wear 'em as you ride up, that just defeats the purpose.
戴著這個我他媽的看不見路啊！
Well I can't see in this fucking thing!
呼吸都不能了，更看不見路啊！
I can't breathe in this fucking thing, and I can't ride in this fucking thing!
去你們的吧，我回家了！
Well fuck all y'all, I'm going home!
我看著我老婆工作了一整天
Ya know I watched my wife work all day
就給你們這些不知感謝的小兔崽子 縫了30個面罩
gettin' thirty bags to get ready for you ungrateful sonsabitches,
你們就知道抱怨，抱怨，抱怨
and all I hear is criticize, criticize, criticize.
從現在開始，別想不給錢就讓我做事了！
From now on, don't ask me or mine for nothin'!
聽著...
Now look…
別忘了我們為什麼來的
Let's not forget why we're here.
我們是來殺山上那個黑鬼的
We gotta killer nigger over that hill there.
給他們好好上一課
And we gotta make a lesson outta 'em.
我不懂了
Okay, I'm confused.
袋子戴著還是拿掉啊
Are the bags on or off.
我覺得…我們都覺得… 用這袋子挺好的
I think… we all think… the bags was a nice idea.
－ 是啊 － 是啊
– Yeah. – Yeah.
但我沒有別的意思啊， 它們完全可以做得更好吧
But not pointing 'ny fingers, they could have been done better.
所以要不然…這次就不戴了
So how about… no bags this time,
但下次，我們把袋子弄好點， 然後就全副武裝
but next time, we do the bags right, and then we go full regalia.
我拿下來了
I get my bag off.
等等！
Wait a minute!
我沒說不用戴了啊
I didn't say no bags.
但沒人能看見路啊
But nobody can see.
所以？
So?
所以，看見路更好啊
So, it be nice to see.
該死的！這可是突襲好嗎！
Goddamit! This is a raid!
我看不見，你也看不見，那又怎樣啊！
I can't see, you can't see. So what?
關鍵是馬能看見不就行了嗎！
All that matters is can the fuckin' horse see!
這才是突襲！
That's a raid!
跑哪去了！
Where's this shit!
他在那！
There he is!
把那黑鬼從馬車下面弄出來
Get that nigger out from under 'at wagon.
把那白人也從馬車堜鴠X來！
And get that nigger lover out o'the wagon!
黑鬼不在馬車下面！
That nigger ain't down here!
－ 他們跑了！ － 什麼？
– They're gone! – What?
－ 我們被他們耍了！ － 那他們到哪去了？
– They tricked us! – Well where are they?
拜拜咯（德語）
Auf wiedersehen.
殺起來
Bull time.
我們現在殺了他們吧
We get 'em now.
膽小鬼才這樣
Cowards tend to do that.
該死！
Goddammit!
你想來嗎？
Would you care to?
戴著這個真是屁都看不見...
I can't see shit out of this…
他要跑了
He's getting away.
我能搞定
I got 'em.
大老爹要逃走咯
Big Daddy's getting away.
我能搞定
I got 'em.
搞定了
Got 'em.
這距離可不近啊
For kids, ain't that short.
你怎麼知道布隆希達的第一任主人是德國人？
How you know Broomhilda's first masters were German?
布隆希達就是個德國名字
Broomhilda is a German name.
如果是他們給她命名的， 那他們就很有可能是德國人咯
If they named her, it stands to reason they'd be German.
你老家有很多女的叫布隆希達嗎？
Lots of gals where you from named Broomhilda?
布隆希達是一個故事角色的名字
Broomhilda is the name of a character
德國的傳說中最有名的一個
in the most popular of all the German legends.
布隆希達還有傳說的？
There's a story 'bout Broomhilda?
哦那當然有了
Oh yes, there is.
你知道是什麼嗎？
Do you know it?
每個德國人都知道的
Every German knows that story.
想讓我告訴你嗎？
Would you like me to tell you?
好吧...
Well…
布隆希達是個公主
Broomhilda was a… princess.
她是沃坦的女兒，沃坦是萬神之神
She was the daughter of Wotan, the god of all gods.
總之反正吧，她的父親因為她變得非常生氣
Anyway, her father is really mad at her.
她做什麼了？
What she do?
我也記不清了 可能是某方面違反了他的命令
I can't exactly remember. I think she disobeys him in some way.
所以他就把她置於山頂
So he puts her on top of the mountain.
布隆希達在山頂？
Broomhilda's on a mountain?
這是德國傳說啊， 故事媮`會有哪堳_出這麼一座山的吧
It's a German legend, there's always going to be a mountain in there somewhere.
然後他還派了一隻噴火的龍來保衛這座山
And he puts a fire breathing dragon there to guard the mountain.
她身邊就圍繞著...
And he surrounds her…
地獄之火
in a circle of hellfire.
所以布隆希達就只能困在那
And there, Broomhilda shall remain,
直到有足夠勇敢的英雄去解救她
unless a hero arises brave enough to save her.
有這樣一個人出現嗎？
Does a fella arise?
是的姜戈，的確有這樣一個人
Yes Django. As a matter of fact, he does.
一個叫西格弗媦w的人
A fella named Sigfried.
那他救了她嗎？
Does Sigfried save her?
是的，很壯觀的
Quite spectacularly so.
他震懾了這座山，因為他毫無畏懼
He scales the mountain, because he's not afraid of it.
殺死了那條龍，因為他毫無畏懼
He slays the dragon, because he's not afraid of him.
穿過地獄之火...
And he walks through hellfire…
因為為了布隆希達，這一切值得
because Broomhilda's worth it.
我明白他的感受
I know how he feel.
我覺得現在我也開始有點明白了
I think I'm just starting to realize that.
聽著，姜戈…
Now… Look… Django…
毫無疑問，總有一天，你會救出你的愛人
I don't doubt that one day you will save your lady love.
但我不能讓你沒認清形勢 就貿然去格林威爾
But I can't let you go to Greenville in a good conscious.
密西西比州的奴隸首都啊， 你不能去
Slave Washington, in Mississippi, isn't a place for you to visit.
不管你是不是自由身，那都太危險了
Free or not, it's just too dangerous.
現在我有個問題要問你
But let me ask you a question.
你覺得賞金獵手這職業怎樣？
How do you like the bounty hunting business?
殺白人，還有錢拿？
Kill white folks, and they pay you for it?
有哪點不喜歡哪
What's not to like?
我必須承認，我們合作得不錯
And I have to admit, we make a good team.
我以為我殺了大約翰和小拉什以後 你還在生我的氣
I thought you was mad at me for killin' Big John and Lit'le Raj?
啊，那次啊，你的確有點過分熱心了
Yeah, on that occasion, you were a tad overzealous,
但通常來說這都是好事
but normally, that's a good thing.
你覺得這個冬天我們繼續合作怎樣？
How'd you like to partner up for the winter?
繼續合作是什麼意思？
What'd ya mean partner up?
冬天你和我一起做事，直到春天冰雪融化
You work with me through the winter till the snow melts.
我的賞金分你三分之一
I give you a third of my bounties.
冬天我們可以好好掙點錢， 等到了雪融化的時候，
So we make some money this winter, and when the snow melts,
我會親自帶你去格林威爾， 弄清楚他們把你老婆賣去了哪
I'll take you to Greenville myself, and we'll find where they sent your wife.
你為什麼要關心我的事？
Why you care what happen to me?
為什麼要關心我能不能找到我老婆？
Why you care if I find my wife?
很顯然...
Frankly…
我以前從未賦予過誰人身自由
I've never given anybody their freedom before.
現在我做到了， 就自認為對你是有責任的
And now that I have, I feel vaguely responsible for you.
再說了，我一個德國人碰到了真人版 的西格弗媦w耶，這可是大事
Plus when a German meets a real life Sigfried, that's kind of a big deal.
作為一個德國人，我必須幫助你
As a German, I'm obliged to help you
幫你解救心愛的布隆希達
on your quest to rescue your beloved Broomhilda.
哦唷，「殺白人換錢」先生到哪去啦？
Ooh, what happened to mister “I wanna shoot white folks for money”?
他兒子跟他在一起呢
His son's with him.
那更好，他還有心愛的人陪著死
Well good. He'll have a loved one with him.
甚至可以分享互相的遺言呢
Maybe even share a last word.
這比大多數人好多啦
That's better then most of them get,
跟他應得的報應比起來，更是好多了
and a damn sight better then he deserves.
把槍放下
Put down the rifle.
別擔心，我沒生氣
Don't worry, I'm not mad at you.
把史密蒂·巴考爾的傳單拿出來
Just take out Smitty Bacall's handbill.
大聲念
Read it aloud.
當作今天的課程
Consider that today's lesson.
通緝令，死活皆可
Wanted, dead or alive.
史密蒂·巴考爾和史密蒂·巴考爾的...
Smitty Bacall and the Smitty Bacall…
團伙
gang.
他們犯有謀殺和馬車搶…
For murder and stagecoach ro…
搶劫罪
robbery.
七零零零…
Seven zero zero ze-
七千
Seven thousand.
– 七... – 千
– Seven- – Thousand.
史密蒂·巴考爾賞金七千
“Seven thousand dollars for Smitty Bacall,
賞金一千五，他的團伙的每一個...
one thousand and five hundred dollars for each of his gang
– 成… – 成員
– memb… – members.
已經知道的史密蒂·巴考爾團伙有以...
Known members of the Smitty Bacall Gang are as fellows,
– 以下 – 以下
– follows. – follows.
丹迪·邁克爾斯，傑拉德·納什，還有...
Dandy Michaels, Gerald Nash and…
瘋子克雷格·庫恩斯
Crazy Craig Koons.
那就是史密蒂·巴考爾
That is who Smitty Bacall is.
如果史密蒂·巴考爾22歲就開始務農，
If Smitty Bacall wanted to start a farm at twenty-two,
就永遠不會有這張紙了
they would never have printed that.
但是史密蒂·巴考爾呢，他搶劫了馬車
But Smitty Bacall wanted to rob stagecoaches,
為了搶劫還殺人不眨眼
and he didn't mind killing people to do it.
你想要跟我做同樣的事情，來拯救你老婆嗎？
D'you want to save your wife by doing what I do?
我就是做這個的
This is what I do.
我殺人，賣屍體換錢
I kill people, and sell their corpses for cash.
這具屍體可值七千塊呢
This corpse is worth seven thousand dollars.
好了別畏畏縮縮的了，給他來一槍吧
Now quit your pussyfootin' and shoot him.
爸爸？
Pa?
爸！
Pa!
拿著...
Here…
你得留著這張史密蒂·巴考爾的傳單
You need to keep this Smitty Bacall handbill.
為什麼？
Why?
代表好運的
It's good luck.
第一筆賞金的傳單都是要留著的
You always keep the handbill of your first bounty.
這才叫準確
That's accurate.
醫生，姜戈，你們好嗎？
Doctor, Django, how the hell are ya?
你那邊又打死了誰啊？
Who the hell have you got there?
威爾森-洛的團伙
The Wilson-Lowe Gang.
這夥人...他們誰啊？
Who the hell is the Wilson-Lowe Gang?
壞蛋查克·威爾森，鐵公雞鮑比·洛， 還有三個跟班
Bad Chuck Wilson and meaner Bobby Lowe, and three of their acolytes.
啊
Huh.
留在外面就可以，他們也不會跑
Well just leave 'em out here, they ain't goin' nowhere.
別在雪地堹葭菑F，我給你倒點咖啡
Let's comin' outta the snowy snow and git yourself some coffee.
昨天是我生日，吃了蛋糕！
Had a birthday yesterday, got some cake!
真不錯
Pretty good.
在這個寒冷又收穫頗豐的冬天之後
姜戈和舒爾茲醫生下山了， 繼續進發，朝著...
跟著！
Move along!
密西西比州
快，走啊！
Do it, walk!
繼續走
Keep moving.
不要有泥巴就走不動了，走啊
Don't let that mud slow you down, keep going.
跟上
Keep on.
布隆希達 范 夏夫特，27歲
Broomhilda Von Shaft, age twenty-seven,
右臉頰有「R」…
“r” on right cheek…
卡爾文·坎迪
Calvin Candy.
他是密西西比州第四大棉花園的主人， 叫坎迪園
He owns the fourth biggest cotton plantation in Mississippi, Candyland.
「坎迪園」？
Candyland?
哦你聽說過？
Oh so you've heard of it?
沒有奴隸沒聽說過坎迪園的
Ain't no slave that ain't heard of Candyland.
好吧，顯然你老婆現在就在那
Well, apparently that's where you wife is,
這個討厭鬼現在是你老婆的主人
and that's the repelling gentleman who owns her.
我們現在就希望她是在外務工的吧，在田里的
Let's just hope she works in the out, slaying in the field.
哦不，她不會在田里的，老兄
Oh no, she ain't in the field, mate.
她…她很漂亮
She… she pretty.
也很高挑
and she a tall girl, too.
那個之前你在田里打死的傢伙...
The one you tore back up on the nag…
在她臉頰燙了一個「R」，逃跑的標誌
he burnt her runaway on her cheek.
真是該死
They got damned.
她不是做農活的，但也沒辦法在屋子堸筐々F
She no field nigger, but she ain't good enough for the house no more either.
他們會讓她去做慰安婦
They're gonna try to make her comfort girl.
慰安婦是…喔
What's a comfort- Oh.
現在我有自由了...
Now while I got freedom…
也有槍了
Now while I got my gun.
我們應該出價買她嗎？
So do we offer to buy her?
所以…
So…
假如啊…
say…
一個人想買一匹馬…
a man wants to buy a horse…
需要買這匹馬
needs to buy a horse.
他就去了這個農夫的農場，敲了他的門
He walks up to the farmer's farm, he knocks on the farmer's door,
跟農夫買這匹馬。 然後你也知道這個農夫會說什麼，
and asks the farmer to buy his horse. And you know what the farmer says,
農夫說，「不賣。」
the farmer says: “No”.
那我說：去你媽的農夫
Well I say: fuck that farmer.
我要把馬偷走
And I'm stealin' that horse.
也行，但你就成了偷馬賊了 偷馬賊可是要被吊死的
Fair enough, but now you are horse thief, and they hang horse thieves.
且不提馬要被送回給主人了
Not to mention the horse goes back to its original owner,
因為無論如何馬都還是他的
because the horse is still its property.
我們需要她，還需要買賣收據
We need her and we need a bill of sale.
那如果我們不去開口買， 那要怎麼才能找回她？
But if we ain't gonna try to buy, then how we gonna get it?
我能不能提個建議，替補方案？
May I offer an alternative plan for action?
說吧
Go ahead.
這個人他去了農場，敲了門
The man walks up to the farmer's farm, he knocks on the farmer's door,
他不是說要買馬，而是說要買農場
and asks not to buy the horse, but the farm,
並且提出了天價的交易，這個農夫不得不答應
and makes an offer so ridiculous, the farmer's forced to say yes.
我們要買坎迪園啊？
We're gonna offer to buy Candyland?
不，那太大了，但很顯然， 農夫不僅僅只有農場吧
No, it's far too big, but apparently, this farmer ain't all about the farm.
你知不知道曼丁戈？（指斗奴隸）
How much do you know about mandingo fighting?
什麼？
What?
你能不能化妝成一個這樣的交易高手？
Can you convincingly masquerade of someone who's an expert on mandingo fighting?
幹嘛？
Why?
因為我要扮演一個 杜塞爾多夫來的大買家
Because my character is that of a big money buyer from Dusseldorf,
來格林威爾想要砸錢進入這個曼丁戈圈子
here in Greenville to buy my way into the mandingo fight game,
你扮演的呢就是我聘來的曼丁戈高手 幫我完成這個任務的
and your character is the mandingo expert I hired to help me do it.
他們叫那「獨眼龍查理」
They call that “One-Eyed Charly”.
你們好
Bonjour.
你好，黑珍珠（法語）
Bonsoir, p'tite femme noire,
我們是來見卡爾文·坎迪先生的
we are here to see Mr. Calvin Candy.
進來
Enter.
謝謝
Thank you.
你要我演個黑人的黑奴買家？
You want me to play a black slaver?
沒有比黑人的黑奴買家更差勁的人了吧
Ain't nothin lower than a black slaver.
黑人的黑奴買家比管家的黑奴還差啊
A black slaver is lower than a head house nigger.
老兄，那可真是有點差
And buddy, that's pretty fuckin' low.
那就照著那個演
Then play him that way,
演出個黑奴買家的樣子來
give me your black slaver.
舒爾茲醫生！
Dr. Schultz!
能再見面真高興啊
Good to see you again.
摩吉先生
Mr. Moguy.
謝謝你幫忙安排這次見面
Thank you for your assistance in creating the opportunity for this appointment.
別，這是我的工作嘛
Nonsense, it's my job.
所以這就是大名鼎鼎的獨眼龍查理啊
So, this is the One-Eyed Charly I've heard so much about.
這是自由人姜戈
Yes, this is Django Freeman.
姜戈，這是坎迪先生的律師， 萊奧尼·摩吉
Django, this is Mr. Candie's lawyer, Leonide Moguy.
叫我萊奧
Just call me Leo.
卡爾文在朱麗葉斯·凱撒廳，跟我來吧？
Calvin's in the Julius Caesar room, y'all wanna follow me?
你跟坎迪先生共事多久了？
How long have you been associated with Mr. Candie?
我和卡爾文的父親一起上寄宿學校的時候， 我們才大概11歲
Oh, Calvin's father and I were about eleven when we went to boarding school together.
卡爾文的祖父讓我上的法學院
Calvins' father father put me through law school.
所以可以這麼說，我生來就是給卡爾文當律師的
One could almost say, I was raised to be Calvin's lawyer.
那就是說你跟黑奴沒什麼兩樣嘛
One could almost say, you's a nigger.
你說什麼？
What did you say?
我說…
I say…
沒什麼沒什麼，他說話就這樣
Real nothing, he's just being cheeky.
見坎迪先生之前，我還有什麼需要知道的嗎？
Now, anything else about Mr. Candie that I should know before I meet him?
他比較親法
Yes, he is a bit of a Francophile.
哪個文明人不是呢？
Ah, what civilized people aren't?
他喜歡別人叫他法語的「先生」而不是英語的
And he prefers Monsieur Candie to Mister Candie.
那就隨著他來好了（法語）
Hmm, si c'est cela qu'il prefere.
他不說法語的，不要跟他說法語， 那會讓他難堪
He doesn't speak French. Don't speak French to him, it'll embarrass him.
翻到上面啊，轉過來
Get back on top now, turn around.
這就對了
There you go.
你是為什麼要加入曼丁戈這行？
Why do you want to get in the mandingo business?
不準備讓你的手下來個正式的介紹嗎？
You don't intend to allow your second to make the proper introductions?
別拖拖拉拉的，回答問題
Quit stalling now. Answer the question.
真話很難聽哦？
The awful truth?
我就是無聊了嘛
Pff, I'm bored.
這個看上去挺好玩的
This seems like a good bit of fun.
那過來吧
Well, come on over.
這堨縞斯菮O，確實挺好玩的
We got us a fight goin' on, that's a good bit of fun.
跟我一起去吧檯吧
Won't you accompany me to the bar?
在這房子堣ㄔi以亂闖，甚至連我都知道的
You don't go ahead in a house, white man, even I know that.
- 舒爾茲醫生... - 我真是高興...
Dr. Schultz… – What a real pleasure-
繼續打啊黑鬼們!
Keep fighting, niggers!
我必須說，這是個榮幸
.. and I might add, an honor.
很榮幸見到你，請坐請坐， 這是我的榮幸
Honored to meet you, please have a seat, the pleasure's all mine.
給自由人姜戈倒酒，他要什麼都行
Get Freeman Django here whatever he wants.
我要甜杜松子波本
And I'll have sweet gin bourbon.
加把勁，照我說的打！
You go way, boy, you do what I tell you!
他真是強壯威猛！
He's got big and strong!
來啊！
Com'on now!
啊，他沒照著我說的打，老天啊
Ah, he's not doing what I told him. For God sake.
打得好，路易奇，動作再快點（意大利語）
Bravo, Luigi, cosi e dai. De casse piu rapido.
加把力啊，這是搏命好嗎！
Com'on now boys, this a fight to the death!
打那頭野獸，不然你就死了！
Hit that animal or you're ain't!
在地毯上打，回到地毯上面
Ecco i con la spola tappeto. La spola tappeto giu.
大弗雷德，加把力！
Big Fred, com'on!
現在把他翻過來吧！
Turn him around, now!
使點力啊！
Use your strength, boy!
加把力啊，用力打！
Com'on now, use your strength!
這就對了！
There you go!
看看這個！
Look at that!
我告訴過你了，這人是野獸啊
Yeah I told you, this is a wild man.
照我說的打
Do what I told you, boy.
這就對了！
Here you go!
啊，不！
Ah. No! Aah!
照我說的打，把他壓在地上
Do what I told you. Ground him back, boy.
打後背！
Ground him back!
啊，不要輸！
Uh, you no lose!
不！不！
No! No!
終結他吧
Finish him.
上啊，終結他！
Go on, boy, finish him!
這就是為什麼他們叫我大弗雷德！
That's why they call him big Fred!
貨真價實
Worth every penny.
永別了路易奇
Well, arrivederchi, Luigi!
起來吧孩子，休息一下
Com'on up now boy, get yourself a rest,
你打得漂亮，真的
you did a fine job, a real fine job.
可以過來了
Proceed in.
龍舌蘭
Tequila.
你叫什麼？
What's your name?
姜戈
Django.
能拼一下嗎？
Can you spell it?
D, J, A, N, G, O.
D不發音
The D is silent.
我知道
I know.
我們走了
Umberto, andiamo.
摩吉先生
Mr. Moguy,
我需要你幫我好好照顧這位新人
I want you to take care o' my new boy here.
給他找個房間，一張舒服的床
You find him a room with a soft bed,
找一頭小馬駒，幫他舔傷口
and you bring him up a pony to lick his pawl.
準備好明天早上去坎迪園，知道了嗎？
You be ready to travel to Candyland tomorrow mornin' now, you hear?
遵命
Yessir, Mr. Candy.
啊，走之前，羅斯科， 給弗雷德來一大杯啤酒
Oh before you go, Roscoe, get Fred here a tall beer.
好好享受吧
You enjoy that, boy.
你自己贏來的
You've earned it.
是
Yessir.
你的名字叫什麼？
What's your name, boy?
他是姜戈，自由人
His name is Django Freeman.
嗯
Hm-hm.
你從哪塈鋮鴘漸L？
Where did ya dig him up?
很多偶然的事件讓我認識了姜戈
A fortuitous turn of events brought Django and myself together.
我有聽過你的傳言
I've heard tell about you.
我聽說你告訴每個人說 曼丁戈沒什麼好的
I heard you've been telling ev'rybody that mandingos are not damn good,
說賣的都是不值錢的，我挺好奇啊
ain't nothing nobody is selling is worth buying, I'm curious.
你是怎麼成為曼丁戈專家的？
What makes you such a mandingo expert?
我好奇的是你有什麼好奇的？
I'm curious what makes you so curious?
- 你剛才說什麼？ - 冷靜點布奇
– What did you say, boy? – Calm down Butch.
對方沒有惡意...
No offense given…
那我當然沒感到什麼惡意了
None taken.
坎迪先生...
Uh, Monsieur Candie…
請向我說明你的疑問吧，不勝感激
Uhm, I'd appreciate if you could direct your line of inquiry toward me.
一
One.
你什麼喝的都沒有點，我給你弄點好喝的吧
You do not have anything to drink, can I get you a tasty refreshment.
當然！我要啤酒
Yes! I'll have a beer.
好極了
Wunderbar.
羅斯科，給這個大鬍子來杯啤酒
Roscoe, a beer for the man with the beard,
我要波利尼西亞珍珠雞尾酒， 不要把朗姆酒灑了
and I will have a Polynesian Pearl Diver, do no spill the rum.
醫生...
Doc…
我是個老練的奴隸主，你是... 你是個新手吧
I'm a seasoned slaver, you are- well, you are a neophyte,
我只是在試探這個牛仔 有沒有在佔你的便宜
I'm simply trying to ascertain if this cowboy here is taking advantage of you.
我十分敬重您，坎迪先生
With all due respect, Monsieur Candie,
我並不是找你要建議的
I didn't seek you out for your advice.
我是找你用超過市場價的錢買黑奴的
I sought you out to purchase a fighting nigger at above top dollar market price.
我注意到身邊還有一大群觀眾啊
I was under the impression when you granted me an audience,
我們是要談生意的吧
it would be to discuss business.
但我們還沒開始談生意吧
But we weren't talking business yet.
剛才只是在談談我的好奇心
We were discussing my curiosity.
羅斯科，可可，出去玩吧
Roscoe, Coco, go outside and play.
西芭
Sheba,
你留下
you stay right there.
我知道你沒喊我
I know you didn't name me.
乾杯
Prost.
Jambo.
據摩吉說
Now according to Moguy,
如果我跟你做生意， 就等於是跟你們倆做生意
if I do business with you, I'm doin' business with both of y'all.
他負責觀察，你負責掏錢，是吧？
He does the eyeballin', you the billfold, is that it?
你說話還挺直白啊，不過大概就是這樣
Well, you don't make it sound too flattering, but more or less, yeah.
所以...
So…
聰明人
Bright Boy,
摩吉說你見過我的黑人們了
Moguy tells me you looked over my African flesh,
你沒有什麼特別感興趣的啊？
and you was none too impressed, huh?
值得花大價錢的沒有
Not for top dollar.
那我們就沒有什麼好談的了
Well then we got nothing more to talk about.
你看，你想要從我這買個能打的
You see, you wanna buy a beat ass nigger from me,
那些都是我在賣的能打的了
those was all the beat ass niggers I wanna sell, so…
他不想買你在賣的
He don't wanna buy the niggers you wanna sell.
他要買你不想賣的
He wants the nigger you don't wanna sell.
我不想賣的我不賣
I don't sell the niggers I don't wanna sell.
你肯定不會賣你最好的
Well, hm. You won't sell your best.
第二好的也不會賣
You won't even sell your second best.
但是你第三好的... 估計你也不會賣
But your third best you don't want to sell him either…
但是如果我出個天價， 你肯定會考慮考慮的
but if I made you an offer so ridiculous you'd be forced to consider it…
誰知道你會怎麼想呢
who knows what could happen?
你定義的「天價」是多少？
And what do you consider ridiculous?
對於一個真正有天賦的，「對的人」？
For a truly talented specimen, well “The Right Nigger”?
你覺得多少錢合適，姜戈？
How much would you say, Django?
一萬二
Twelve thousand dollars.
先生們
Gentlemen…
剛才我還是好奇
You had my curiosity.
現在我興趣很大啊
Now you have my attention.
威利...威利
Willie… Willie.
停一停，停一停
Hold up! Hold up.
啊
Aah.
先生們早上好
Good morning, gentlemen.
舒爾茲醫生好，多美的早晨啊
Good Dr. Schultz. Beautiful morning isn't it?
找不到比這更好的了
You couldn't have picked a better one.
請跟我們一起坐一坐馬車吧
Please, won't you take a ride with us here in the Victorian.
噢非常感謝
Oh, thank you very much.
把你的馬綁在後面
Tie your horse up back there.
姜戈！
Django!
我跟身邊的大多數人還是要保持距離的
Well I part company from many of my phenologist colleagues,
因為我覺得會有人 是比聰明還要更聰明
cause I believe there's a level above bright,
比有天賦、忠誠還要更有天賦和忠誠 普通黑人是做不到的
above talented, above loyal that a nigger can aspire.
我會說這樣一個黑人只能是萬里挑一的
Say one nigger that just pops up on ten thousand.
一個特別優秀的黑人
The exceptional nigger.
天氣不錯吧
Bright day uh, Bright Boy?
太陽升起來了
Sun is up.
照在每個人身上
Shinin' on all of us.
請坐吧，醫生
Have a seat, Doc.
十分榮幸
Great an honor.
是我們的榮幸
The honor is all ours.
謝謝
Thank you.
但我相信，只要有時間， 特別優秀的黑人，比如現在這位聰明人
.. but I do believe that given time, exceptional niggers like Bright Boy here,
總會出現的，只要沒有自由…
will come if not freedom…
更多的自由…
more freedom…
聰明人
Bright Boy,
你就是那萬分之一
you are that one in ten thousand.
現在玩的是跟上，不是追上，黑鬼
The name of the game is keep up, not catch up, nigger.
敢碰槍你們就死定了
Touch your guns, you're dead.
大家冷靜！
Everybody calm down!
我都看到了，不要衝動
I saw the whole thing, no harm done.
開玩笑呢吧，這個黑鬼...
Are you- are you kiddin' me, this nigger-
我說了不要動手！ 把手從槍上拿開！
I said no harm done! Now take your hands off your pistol!
布奇！
Butch!
你也一樣
That means you too.
所有人都不許挑釁我的客人
Ev'rybody stop antagonizing my guests.
胡！
Who!
騎回你馬上去
Git back upon your horse.
他把我鎖骨打斷了！
He broke my collarbone!
上帝啊，誰來幫他一下爬到馬上去
For God sake, somebody please help Who here back upon his goddamn horse.
哇，你真是個幸運的黑鬼
Ooh, now you are one lucky nigger.
聽你頭兒的話吧，小鬼
You got to listen to your boss, white boy.
噢，全心全意為您服務啊
Oh I'm a good walk in any moonlight for you.
想捧著我的手嗎？
You wanna hold my hand?
威利！我們回家吧
Willie! Take us home.
你眼睛是有問題嗎？
You got a problem with your eyeball, boy?
沒有
No sir.
想我把鞋跟踩進去是吧？
You wan' a boot heel in it?
不想
No sir.
那就別盯著看
Then keep your goddamn eyeballs off me.
再讓我看到這張臭臉，我會讓我更恨我的
Flash that bad look at me again, I give you a reason not to like me.
跟上，黑鬼！
Now move, nigger!
你的黑鬼們得看看清楚我是誰
You niggers gonna understand somethin' 'bout me.
我比這堨籉韝@個白人都值錢
I'm worse than any o'these white men here.
讓他們不要亂看，尤其不要看我
You keep them eyelash inside your ass, you keep them goddamn eyeballs off me.
他還挺粗暴啊是吧
He is a rambunctious sort, ain't it?
確實！
Indeed!
能停一下嗎，我跟他有句話說
May you stop for a moment, so I may put put a word in my man's ear?
我準備要徹底愛上坎迪園的戰士們
Yeah, I'm expecting to fall in love once I see the specimen of Candyland,
所以在那之前，我還是想要
so before that moment, it would be good if I could have
跟我的謀士來個保密戰略會談
a confidential strategy meeting with my… confident.
能不能說說你到底在幹嘛？
You mind tellin' me what the hell you doing?
我已經確認布隆希達就在坎迪園
I've confirmed that Broomhilda's at Candyland.
你確定是她？
Are you sure it's her?
他沒有說她的名字，但確定是位年輕女子
He didn't call her by name, but she's a young lady,
背上有鞭痕，說德語
whip marks on her back, and speaks German.
現在還不好假設什麼
Now while it's not wise to assume,
但這種情況下我看已經很肯定了吧
in this instance, I think it's pretty safe.
關鍵是...
Point being…
不要報仇報得太囂張了
don't get so carried away with your retribution.
都忘了是來這幹嘛的了吧
We lose sight on why we're here.
你覺得我忘了？
You think I lost sight, did I?
是啊！不要再挑釁坎迪了！
Yes, I do! Stop antagonizing Candy!
你要把他手下人都惹毛了， 我們倆就都玩完了
You're going to blow this whole charade, or more than likely get both of us killed,
至少我是不願意死在這 美國密西西比的芝卡索縣
and I, for one, don't intend to die in Chickasaw County, Mississippi, U.S.A.
我沒有挑釁，我這是使點伎倆
I'm not antagonizing. I'm intriguing him.
你在大聲羞辱這些可憐的奴隸啊
You- you're yelling abuse of these poor slaves!
我想起某個...
I recall the man….
讓我當著別人兒子的面殺人的傢伙了 （指之前史密蒂）
who had me killed another man in front o' his son,
他眼皮都不眨啊
and he didn't bat an eye.
還記得嗎？
Remember that?
我當然記得！
Yeah of course I remember!
你說的是...
What you said was…
你說的，這不是我的話...
You said, this ain't my word…
「要我說，你就得染得一身骯髒」
“In my word you got to get dirty”.
我正在這麼做，弄得骯髒點
So that's what I'm doing. I'm getting dirty.
你解釋得是不錯，但是...
Well you're paraphrasing a tad, but…
這一般是...
that was it generally, just…
坎迪園見吧
see you at Candyland.
好了黑鬼們！
Alright niggers!
做正事了
Back at it.
你也一樣，白鬼
That means you too, moonlight.
達達尼昂！
I'll 'be. D'Artagnan!
天，你怎麼會幹逃跑這麼蠢的事？
Now well, why do a fool thing like run off?
我不能再打架了，坎迪先生
I can't fight no more, Monsieur Candy.
你當然能！
Yes you can!
你或許不能贏，但肯定還能打啊
Y?u m?ght n?t b? ?bl? t? w?n, but y?ur ??? ??n f?ght.
斯通瑟，你能不能讓這些狗閉嘴
Mr. Stonesipher, would you please shut these goddamn dogs up,
我都聽不到自己的思考了！
I cannot hear myself think!
噓，瑪莎！噓！安靜！
Hush now, Marsha! Hush up, Marsha! Marsha, hush up!
讓這些狗不要煩這黑鬼了！
Hey, get these goddamn dogs away from this nigger!
好了孩子
Well now boy…
- 從樹上下來吧 - 是
Gidown o' that tree. – Yes sir.
他逃了有多久了？
How long was he lose?
一整晚...
A night…
一整天...
day…
頭天還有半個晚上
Half the other night.
逃了有多遠？
How far he git off property?
大概二十英里
Bout twenty miles off prop.
已經挺遠了，他的腳還跛著
Pretty fer, conside'ing that limp he got.
摩吉先生，達達尼昂週五要跟誰打？
Mr. Moguy, who was D'Artagnan supposed to fight on Friday?
一個新人吧
One of this new lot.
看他現在的樣子，找個印第安瞎子 都可以把他打得落花流水
The way he looks now, a blind Indian wouldn't bet a bead on 'em.
求你了坎迪先生，我不能， 不能再繼續打了，我不能...
Please Mr. Candy, I ain't got it, ain't it no more, I can't-
不不不，不要求我...
No no no no, now no beggin'…
不要玩弄我柔軟的內心啊
No playin' on my soft heart.
你現在的確有麻煩了，孩子
You're in trouble, now son.
我為你花了500塊
I done paid 500 dollars for you…
我花了500塊呢...
When I pay 500 dollars…
我想要看到你給我打五次， 把別人打翻，打死
I expect to get five fights outta a nigga 'fore he rollover and play dead.
你得明白...我是個生意人
Got to understand, I'm… I'm running a business here!
你，你只打了三次
You- you fought three fights.
可是三次都贏了！
But I won everyone!
的確，的確，
Yes you did. Yes you did,
但最後一次，輸和贏說不清， 算是矇混過關了
but that last one, you muddled the line between winning and losing.
事情還是這樣
Still the fact remain.
我花了五百塊，是要你們給我打五場！
I pay 500 dollars, I want five goddamn fights!
我的五百塊要怎麼辦啊，啊？
So what 'bout my five hundred dollars, huh?
我的五百塊要怎麼辦？
What about my five hundred dollars?
你來給我補償啊？
You go n' reimburse me?!
你是不是都不知道補償是什麼意思？
You even know what reimburse means?
我會補償你！
I'll reimburse you!
是嗎？
You will?
你要付五百塊…
You pay 500 dollars…
來給這個掃帚都拿不動的傢伙？
for pratic'lly a one eyed Ole'Joe ain't fit to push a broom?
他不會的
No, he won't.
他只是看不下去你調戲那個人了
He's just tired of you toyin' with him, is all.
其實我也看不下去了
Matter o' facts, so am I.
我們可不會給那小鬼花一分錢
But we ain't payin' a penny for that pickaninny,
他們又沒有用，是吧，醫生？
ain't got no use for 'em, ain't that right, Doc?
你也聽到了！
You heard 'em!
你得原諒斯通瑟現在這樣盯著你看
I'm gonna have to excuse Mr. Stonesipher slack jaw gaze, he…
他這輩子都沒見過像你這樣的黑人
he ain't never seen a nigger like you ever in his life.
是吧，斯通瑟？
Ain't that right, Mr. Stonesipher?
是啊
That right.
既然這樣
That matter…
那就算了
Won't have that.
現在
Now…
反正你也不會買這小鬼
Sin'e as you won't pay a penny for this pickaninny here…
你不介意我隨便怎麼處置吧
you won't mind me handlin' this nigger anyway I see fit?
他是你的奴隸
He's your nigger.
斯通瑟先生？
Mr. Stonesipher?
讓瑪莎和她的好夥伴們 送達達尼昂上黑鬼的天堂吧
Let Marsha and her bitches send D'Artagnan to nigger heaven.
瑪莎！把黑鬼弄來！
Marsha! Git the nigger!
你的頭兒似乎還不大適應這些啊
Your boss looks a little green around the gills
還要加入這血腥的黑人打架事業？
for a blood sport like 'nigger fightin'?
沒有
No.
他只是不習慣看到一個人被狗咬死而已
He just ain't use to seein' a man ripped apart by dogs, is all.
那你挺習慣的？
You are used to it?
我只是比他更習慣美國
I'm just a little more use to American's than he is.
坎迪先生
Now… Monsieur Candy,
隨時等你準備好
whenever you're ready.
我們已經走了五小時了，讓你來展示庫存
We rode five hours so you could show off your stock.
談正事吧
Let's git to it.
因為目前來看，如果這個人也是...
Cause as of now, if he's an example…
我可不大滿意
I ain't impressed.
跟我來
Follow me.
在左邊站好隊
Line up to the left here now niggers.
這就對了
That's it.
站直線，站直線
You gimme a line, gimme a line.
站好直線，馬上！
Get in line here. Right now!
你好啊，斯蒂文！
Hello, Steven my boy!
啊啊，你好啊主子
Yeah yeah yeah, hello my ass.
那個騎馬的黑人是誰啊
Who this nigger up on that nag?
哦斯蒂文，你早飯不是吃了馬肉嗎
Oh Steven, you have nags for breakfast.
怎麼啦，怎麼脾氣這麼壞， 是想我了嗎？
What's the matter, why so ornery, you miss me, huh?
哦哦當然了，我想你就像屋子想念鮮花
Oh-oh yes sir, I miss you like a home miss flower,
像嬰兒想念媽媽的奶
like a - like a- a baby miss Mum n' Teddy,
就像我想念鞋子堛漸衈Y
I miss you like I misses a rock in my shoe.
我得問問你， 那匹馬上的黑人是誰啊？
Now I ask you: who this nigger, on that nag?
嘿白頭髮的
Hey Snowball.
如果你想知道我叫什麼， 或者我的馬叫什麼，自己問我
If you wanna know my name or the name of my horse, you ask me.
騎馬的，你叫誰白頭髮呢？
Just who the hell you callin' Snowball, horse boy?
我會一巴掌把你的屁股揍下來摔地上...
I'll snap your black ass of that nag there in the mud-
哇哦，哇哦，斯蒂文，斯蒂文
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Steven, Steven.
娛樂點嘛
Let's keep it funny.
這位姜戈，是自由人
Django here is a Freeman.
- 這個黑鬼？ - 正是他
– This nigger here? – That nigger there.
讓我至少介紹介紹你們倆吧
Let me at least introduce the two of you.
姜戈，這是另外一個 跟你一樣態度惡劣的黑人，斯蒂文
Django, this is another cheeky black bugger like yourself, Steven.
斯蒂文，這是姜戈
Steven, this is Django.
你們倆肯定要恨死對方
You two ought to hate each other.
卡爾文，這黑鬼到底誰啊你還要取悅他？
Calvin, just who the hell is this nigger you feel the need to entertain?
姜戈，以及他的朋友，穿灰衣服的 舒爾茲醫生，是我們的顧客
Django, and his friend in grey here Dr. Schultz are customers,
也是我們的客人，斯蒂文
and they are our guests, Steven,
你這老混蛋，一定要好客點啊
and you, you old decrepit bastard, are to show them every hospitality.
- 懂了沒？ - 是，我正在試著弄懂
You understand that? – Yessir, here I'm understandin',
但我還是不明白我幹嘛要對這黑鬼說好話？
but I don't know why I gotta take lip off this nigger?
你不需要知道為什麼，明白了？
You don't hafta know why. Do you understand?
是，我明白了
Yes sir, I understand.
好的！
Oh good!
他們要住一晚，去客房收拾兩間出來
They're spendin' the night, go up in the guest bedrooms and get two ready.
他還要呆在這大宅堙H
He gonna stay in the Big House?
斯蒂文，他是做買賣奴隸的，不一樣的
Steven, he's a slaver. It's different.
要住這大宅？
In the Big House?
你難道有問題啊？
Well you gotta problem with that?
不不不，我沒問題
No, no no I got no problem with it,
我是覺得他們會吧床啊床單啊枕頭啊都燒了
with you I gotta problem with burnin' the bed, the sheets, the pillow cases,
等他那黑不溜秋的傢伙一走就會！
ev'rything up when this black ass motherfuckers gone!
那也是我的問題，燒也是燒我的
Now that is my problem, they are mine to burn!
你的問題就是要給我留個好印象
Now your problem right now is making a good impression.
我需要你現在就開始著手解決這個問題
And I want you to start solving that problem right now,
快把他們的房間收拾好！
and git them goddamn rooms ready!
是的，坎迪先生
Yes sir, Monsieur Candie.
快去吧
Go on now.
真不敢相信你帶個黑鬼來大宅堶
Can't believe you brought a nigger to stay in the Big House.
你接管這房子還真是無法無天了
You get a rollin' over and it's God man free right now.
他對你意見很大啊
He had a lip on you.
黑鬼來我們莊園，怎麼回事啊
A nigger in the estate part. What shit is that!?
好了
Now.
我美若天僊的姐姐呢！
Where is my beautiful sister!
在這兒呢！
There she is!
舒爾茲醫生，這位美麗的南方少婦 就是我守寡的姐姐
Dr. Schultz, this attractive southern belle is my widowed sister.
親愛的，你就是我們眼中的明珠
Darling, you are a diamond for tired eyes.
向大家介紹一下， 這位是勞拉·李·坎迪-菲茲威利
May I present to you Lara Lee Candie-Fitzwilly.
切斯特，羅尼，查理，快點去那座山
Chester, Rodney, Chicken Charlie, you'll git your ass up on that hill.
快點查理，走了
Com'on Charlie, go on now.
走，快點，你知道在哪
Go, com'on now. You know where it is.
像被繩子拴著一樣快點！
Like you on a rope!
黑鬼不許慢慢走！跑起來！
Niggers don't walk 'round here! Niggers run!
- 啊，坎迪先生？ - 嗯？
– Ah, Monsieur Candie? – Hmm?
關於那件事，我們說到那個黑人女孩的？
About that matter, about the nigger girl we were talking about?
黑人女孩？
Nigger girl?
你說過她會說德語的？
Yeah, I believe you mentioned she spoke German?
啊是啊，希爾蒂，她怎麼了？
Ah yes, Hildi, what about her?
你覺得在展示商品之前 能讓她來我房間嗎？
Do you think before the demonstration you could send her around to my room?
你這狡猾的傢伙！
You little Dickens, you!
為什麼不呢
I don't see why not.
斯蒂文，你帶他們去房間以後，叫希爾蒂去
Steven, when you get through showing them to their rooms, go fetch Hildi,
讓她洗洗乾淨，弄點香， 送去舒爾茲醫生的房間
get her cleaned up and smellin' nice, and sent over to Dr. Schultz's room.
其實呢，坎迪先生... 我還有事情沒告訴你
Actually, Monsieur Candie, it's- it's somethin' I ain't tole you that yet.
什麼事？
What?
希爾蒂還在那個熱盒子塈b著
Uh, Hildi in The Hot Box.
她在那幹嘛？
What's she doin' there?
你覺得她在幹嘛，熱盒子嘛， 她在受懲罰呢
What 'cha think she doin' there, in The Hot Box, she bein' punished.
- 她怎麼了？ - 她又逃跑了
– What did she do? – She ran off again.
我的天哪斯蒂文，我不在的時候多少人逃跑了啊？
Jesus Christ Steven, how many people ran away while I was gone?
就倆
Two.
她什麼時候跑的？
And when did she go?
昨晚，他們...他們今早把她抓回來的
Last night, they- they brought her back this morning.
斯通瑟的狗把她咬成什麼樣了？
How bad did Stonesipher's dogs tear her up?
她還算幸運，狗都出去找達達尼昂了
Lucky for her, they was out chasin' D'Artagnan's ass.
比爾和科迪出去找她的， 然後帶回來了
Bill and Cody went out lookin' for her, found her and brought her back, uh…
她現在被折磨得厲害
Now she a little beat up,
但她那都是自找的， 自己在灌木叢堶捷]
but- but she done that the all damn self, runnin' through them damn bushes and shit.
她在盒子塈b多久了？
How long she been in the box?
你覺得多久了，都在堶惜@整天了！
How long ya think, she been in there all damn day!
這小婊子還有10天要呆呢
And the lit'le bitch got ten more days be in there.
斯蒂文，放她出來
Steven, take her out.
放她出來？為什麼？！
Take her out, why?!
因為我說的，就這樣
Because I said so, that's why.
舒爾茲醫生是我的客人
Dr. Schultz is my guest.
希爾蒂是我的奴僕，南方人民很好客的， 我必須讓她可以見客
Hildi is my nigger, Southern hospitality dictates I make her available to him.
但坎迪先生，她才剛試圖逃跑過
But Monsieur Candie, she just ran off.
天哪斯蒂文， 我們養個說德語的黑奴是為什麼呢，
Jesus Christ Steven, what is the point of havin' a nigger that speaks German,
不就是有德國客人的時候拉出來接客的嗎？
if you can't wheel 'em out when you have a German guest?
我知道對你來說還挺不方便的， 但是，放她出來
Now I realize it is inconvenient but still, you take her ass out!
是的
Yes sir.
勞拉，你能不能和科拉一起
Lara Lee, will you and Cora be responsible for getting
負責把希爾蒂清理乾淨， 讓她可以見舒爾茲醫生？
Hilda cleaned up and presentable for Dr. Schultz here?
沒問題親愛的
Of course, darling.
先生們，十分抱歉， 我真是累壞了，無以言表
Now gentlemen, I do apologize, but I'm wearer for our travels beyond words,
我得先休息休息了
it is time for me to rest my tired ass.
你們都聽到了，全部都去幹活
Ya'all have heard the man, get yar ass, all part of it.
來！過來！
Go! Come here!
去那邊讓她洗洗乾淨， 帶她去醫生那
Get over there, get her cleaned up, bring her back over here to doctor
你...叫什麼名字，舒...
what- what did you say your name is, Schut?
- 舒爾茲 - 舒爾茲！
– Schultz. – Schultz!
把她帶回這堥
Git her back over here, alright girl?
是
Yes sir.
希爾達，你是跟我來呢， 還是打算繼續在那個盒子媞帡琚H
Hilda, you comin’ with me, or you gonna sleep in that lit'le box over here?
女士們好
Hello ladies.
舒爾茲醫生，這位就是布隆希達
Dr. Schultz, may I introduce to you Broomhilda.
希爾蒂，這位是舒爾茲醫生
Hildi, this is Dr. Schultz.
很高興見到你，布隆希達
It's a pleasure to meet you, Broomhilda.
我聽說了你很多好的事情
I've heard a lot of good things about you.
說德語的黑人可不多啊，不是嗎？
Well, it's not often a nigger speaks German, don't you know?
我現在看著你，布隆希達
As I look at you now, Broomhilda,
所有那些由你點燃的熱情都變得合理
I could see all the passion you inspire completely justified.
這位醫生也會說德語！
The doctor here speaks German!
我聽說你也會，是嗎？
And I've been informed you do as well?
乖孩子，說幾句德語
Go ahead girl, speak a little German.
能跟您說德語我很高興
令人驚嘆啊
Astonishing.
進來吧，姑娘
- 還需要我... - 非常感謝
– And I should bring- – Much obliged.
需要我給你倒杯水嗎？
不要害怕
Don't be afraid.
不好意思
我想你應該很久沒有說過德語了
所以我慢慢說
我現在跟你說德語是以防 坎迪的人在偷聽
不好意思
Pardon.
你真美
謝謝
我和一個我們共同的朋友
經歷了重重困難
走了無數的路
來找到你，姑娘
來解救你
喝點水吧
現在，我和這位我們共同的朋友目的都是
把你永遠的帶離這
我沒有朋友
你當然有了
誰？
我不能告訴你
這位朋友呢，很風騷，想要搞得戲劇化一點
那他現在在哪？
就站在那扇門後
向我保證你不會尖叫？
說，「我保證」
我保證
嘿小搗蛋鬼
Hey Little Trouble Maker.
你這油嘴滑舌的傢伙
You silver tongued devil you.
動作快點
不不不，那是晚上喝的，去樓下...
- 真是太麻煩了 - 最喜歡他的人是你吧
你知道我喜歡什麼的
坎迪先生，他們都是很好的人選， 毫無疑問
Look Monsieur Candie, they were all fine specimens, no doubt about it.
但目前最好的三個是
But the best three, by far, were:
桑森...
Sampson…
- 那個人叫什麼來著？ - 高迪
Well, what's his name again? – Goldie.
高迪，還有愛斯基摩人喬
Goldie… and Eskimo Joe.
順便問問他為什麼叫愛斯基摩人喬？
By the way, why is he called Eskimo Joe?
哦，你永遠別想知道這些外號怎麼來的
Oh, you never know how these nigger nicknames get started.
他本來叫喬，可能突然有一天 他說他覺得自己好冷呢，誰知道
His name was Joe, maybe one day he said he was cold, who knows?
不論如何
Well, regardless,
桑森是最好的
Samson's your best,
我們都知道了
we all know that,
你永遠不會賣的，我也看得出來， 他是冠軍的料
you will never sell him, and I can see why, he's a champion.
三個都是冠軍
Hm-hm-hm! All three are champions.
桑森是冠軍
Samson's champion.
另外兩個屬於比較好的
Them other two pretty good.
卡爾文，那個黑鬼...你竟然讓...
Calvin, what that nigger- you let-
沒關係，沒關係
That's alright, that's alright.
你得瞭解，坎迪先生
You have to understand Monsieur Candie,
我雖然在這黑人打架生意堶惇O新手
while admittedly a neophyte in the nigger fight game,
我在歐洲巡迴馬戲團的生意方面 還是有點經驗的
I do have a little bit of a background in the European traveling circus.
是吧？
Is that right?
所以...說到展示，我還是有點想法的
Hence… I have big ideas when it comes to presentation.
我需要的不僅僅是個壯漢
I need something more than just a big nigger.
他必須...會表現
He needs to have… panache.
- 會幹嘛？ - 嗯...
– Need to have what what what? – Panache, hum…
- 會招攬顧客！ - 招攬顧客，嗯
– A sense of showmanship! – Showmanship, yes.
我希望可以把他稱作「黑色大力神」
I want to be able to bill him him as the “Black Hercules”.
黑色大力神，好名字啊
Black Hercules, isn't that clever?
聽上去就像「特別黑」似的
More like niggerly.
我說過，再引用一次
I said, and I quote:
「我會為正確的黑人付高價」
“I would pay top dollar for the Right Nigger”.
我不是說愛斯基摩人喬就是錯的...
Now I'm not saying that Eskimo Joe is the wrong nigger per se…
但他真的那麼值得我買嗎？
but is he right as rain?
舒爾茲醫生，我必須讓你知道
Dr. Schultz, I will have you know,
在黑人打鬥比賽堶
there is no one in the nigger fight game that appreciates
沒人會注重什麼表現能力， 大家都看重我卡爾文·坎迪的話
the value of showmanship more than Monsieur Calvin J. Candie.
確實
Nobody.
一個人不能忘記這打鬥比賽中最重要的東西
But one must not forget the most important thing in the nigger fight game.
就是這個黑人必須能打贏
And that is a nigger that can win fights.
這個必須是你前五需要考慮的吧
Now that should be your first, second, third, four, and fifth concern.
有了這個，你確信自己掌握了這個
Now after you have that, and you know you have that,
你才開始考慮包裝問題
then you can start to implement a grand design.
換句話說，第一總是優先
In other words, first thing is first.
第一優先
First thing is first.
我看你倆打得火熱嘛
I see you two gettin' on.
哥擅長的
Famously.
哦坎迪先生，你無法想像
Oh Monsieur Candie, you can't imagine what it's like
四年沒聽過母語是什麼感覺
not to hear you native tongue in four years.
好吧，我都不能想像 在波士頓呆兩周是什麼樣
Well hell, I can't imagine two weeks in Boston.
在波士頓呆兩周， 哦這真是，哈哈哈
Two weeks in Boston, oh that's your- oh man!
在波士頓呆兩周！
Ah, two weeks in Boston!
能用母語交談，這喜悅真是無法表達
I can't express the joy I felt conversing in my mother tongue.
希爾蒂是一個很好的聊天夥伴
And Hildi is a charming conversation companion.
當心哦舒爾茲醫生
Ah be careful now Doctor Schultz,
你可能有點太迷戀黑人了
you might have caught yourself a little dose of Nigella.
這種迷戀可是很厲害的
Nigella's a powerful emotion, boy.
就像一個充滿黑色焦油的池子， 一旦抓住你，你就不能...
It's like a pool of black tar, once it catches your ass, you can't-
是啊，就完了
Yessir, you can't.
我可不知道啊醫生， 你可以把德語的甜言蜜語都甩出來
I don't know doctor, you can lay on all the German sweet talk you want, but
但這位姑娘的眼神都在姜戈身上呢
it looks like this pony's got big eyes for Django.
一般情況下，她的確會注意翱翔的雄鷹吧
Well… naturally, it is the soaring eagle that attracts her attention,
而不是撲騰的雞崽子
not the plucked chicken.
舒爾茲醫生，不要這麼貶低你自己
Dr. Schultz, don't be so down on yourself,
您是位風流倜儻的歐洲紳士
you are quite a dapper European gentleman.
你要弄完這個，要把手臂放進去，聽到沒有...
You gotta finish this, you got to put your elbow in this, this is, do you hear me-
你認識那個黑鬼的，是吧？
You know that nigger, don't ya?
- 誰？ - 誰？
– Who? – Who?
別跟我誰誰的婊子， 你知道我在說誰
Don't who me bitch, you know who I'm talking about!?
桌上那個？
At the table?
我不認識他
I don't know him.
你不認識他？
You don't know him?
不認識
No.
不什麼？
No what?
不，先生
No sir.
你現在沒膽向我撒謊，是吧？
You wouldn't lie to me now, would you?
好吧…
Okay…
那就信你
If- if you say so.
愛斯基摩人喬是個不錯的選手， 毫無疑問
Eskimo Joe's a quality nigger, no doubt about it.
但如果錢在我手堛爾...
But if it was my money…
我是不會付一萬二給他的
I wouldn't pay no twelve thousand dollars for him.
你會開價多少？
What would your price be?
如果我可以大方一點的話
Well, if I was inclined to be generous,
我也不知道我幹嘛要大方一點...
and I don't know why I would be inclined to be generous…
九千...
nine thousand…
可能吧
maybe.
舒爾茲醫生
Dr. Schultz…
我想再搞搞清楚這個講價是怎麼回事啊
Let me reclarify how this whole negotiation came about.
你看，不是我找你來賣黑人給你的吧
You see, it wasn't me who came to you to sell a nigger,
當然不是
Sure, it wasn't.
是你來找我跟我買的
It was you who approached me to buy one.
當然
Sure it was.
現在你那聰明人跟我講的九千塊
Now that nine thousand dollar figure Bright Boy was banding about,
這數字其實跟實際價錢差不多了
that ain't too far off from right,
如果我想給愛斯基摩人喬賣這個價錢
and if I wanted to sell Eskimo Joe for that,
我隨便哪天都能賣出去
I could do so any day of the week.
隨便哪天
Any day.
但正如你在格林威爾所說的，醫生，
But like you said in Greenville doctor,
我不想賣
I don't wanna sell 'em.
只是因為你開了個天價
It was only your ridiculous offer
說是一萬二，我才考慮的
of twelve thousand dollars that made me even consider it.
嗯
Hmm-hmm.
坎迪先生啊，你的確比我要能說會道一些
You know Monsieur Candie, you do possess the power of persuasion.
為什麼不買呢，坎迪先生，成交， 愛斯基摩人喬，一萬二！
Why not, Monsieur Candie, you have a deal, Eskimo Joe, twelve thousand dollars!
好啊，醫生，太好了， 明智的決定！
Hurray, doctor, hurray, and a wise decision, that is!
不過呢，這真是很大一筆錢
However, that is a tremendous amount of money.
如同你有摩吉先生一樣，我也有個律師
And the way you have your Mr. Moguy, I have a lawyer,
一個很小氣的男人，叫塔圖
a persnickety man named Tuttle,
我需要他幫我起草一份法律文書
And I would need my Mr. Tuttle to draw up a legal contract
在我放心完成這麼巨大一份交易之前
before I'd feel comfortable exchanging that amount of money for flesh.
以及我還需要自己選一位醫生 來為愛斯基摩人喬做體檢
Not to mention having Eskimo Joe examined by a physician of my choosing.
那是自然
Naturally.
所以我們大概...
So say I return in about…
- 五天之後回來 - 五天？
.. five days time. – Five days ?!
我和我的律師塔圖一起
With my Mr. Tuttle. And then my Mr. Tuttle
然後他和摩吉先生會自己商討合同細節的
and your Mr. Moguy can hash out the finer details between themselves.
好極了，醫生，好極了
I say splendid Doctor… Splendid.
先生們...
Gentlemen…
我提議敬酒
may I propose a toast…
敬愛斯基摩人喬。哦，我們該叫他
to Eskimo Joe. Or, shall we call him
黑色大力神
the Black Hercules.
敬黑色大力神
To the Black Hercules.
敬黑色大力神！
The Black Hercules!
黑色大力神…
The Black Hercules…
你是對的，醫生， 這名字確實漲士氣
You was right, Doctor, that name do help pay an ass.
希爾蒂
Hildi…
我這兒沒有酒了
I'm outta drink, girl.
希爾蒂...在大宅子堶惆糽^一大桌人， 感覺怎麼樣？
So Hildi… how you like servin' at the big table in the big house, huh?
坎迪先生跟你說話了，你就回答
When Monsieur Candy talk to you, you answers.
我很喜歡，坎迪先生
I like it a lot, Monsieur Candie.
嗯
Hmm-hmm.
比躺在那個滾燙的盒子媦R吼是好多了
It's a lot better than sizzling in that hot box,
或者是在荊棘叢堸k跑
or draggin' your ass through a bramble bush.
可能比不上曼丁戈那麼好玩啊
Maybe it's not quite as much fun as getting the pleasure o' the mandingos,
- 是吧甜心？ - 噢，她很喜歡看的
huh sugar babe? – Hmm oh, she like them new.
- 比如桑森，是吧？ - 是
– Like Simpson, huh? – Yessir.
- 坎迪先生， - 嗯？
– You know Monsieur Candie, – Hmm?
醫生可能會有興趣看看 希爾蒂被鞭子抽過的背呢
the doctor here might be interested in seein' Hildi's peeled back,
他家鄉可沒有這麼多黑奴吧
since how they don't have many niggers where he come from.
舒爾茲醫生，你剛才跟希爾蒂在一起的時候
Dr. Schultz, when you was alone with Hildi here,
你們是只說了說德語，還是脫過衣服了？
did- didja just speak German, or did ya git her clothes off?
我們只是聊了聊...
No, we just talked and…
噢，所以你還沒見過她的背吧？
Oh so- so you haven't seen her back?
我沒有...
I haven't-
不不不，斯蒂文是對的， 你可能會感興趣
No no no, now Steven's right, you might find this interesting.
希爾蒂，快，把裙子脫了， 給醫生看看你的背，來啊！
Hildi, com'on take off your dress, show Dr. Schultz your back here, go on!
啊，卡爾文，我才把她打扮得漂漂亮亮的
Uh, Calvin, I just got her all dressed up and looking nice.
但是，勞拉，舒爾茲醫生是杜塞爾多夫來的， 他們那堨i沒有黑奴
But… Lara Lee, Dr. Schultz is from Dusseldorf,they don't got niggers there.
他又是學醫的
He's a man of medicine.
我肯定他會喜歡的，黑鬼對疼痛的忍耐力啊
I'm sure it would fascinate him, the niggers endurance for pain.
這些黑鬼很強硬的， 醫生，這毫無疑問
These niggers are tough Dr. Schultz, no doubt about it.
希爾蒂悲傷大概有四條疤
Hilda's got somethin' like four lashes on her back.
勞拉，你... 幹嘛不把帶子解開？
Lare Lee, just get- why don't you lose her goddamn mat?
看看啊，醫生，就像一幅畫一樣，瞧瞧
Look a' that, doctor, it's like a painting, look at that.
卡爾文！
Calvin!
我們在吃飯，沒人想看她被鞭子打過的背！
We are eating, ain't no one wanna look at her whipped up back!
好好好...
Fine. Fine, fine fine fine…
吃完晚飯吧，斯蒂文，等吃完
After the dinner, Steven. After dinner.
等喝白蘭地的時候吧，先生們怎麼樣？
During the brandies, gentlemen. Uh?
科拉，過來把她帶走！
Cora, come get this girl!
- 她被弄得一團糟了 - 好的
She all messed. – Yes ma'am?
噢！怎麼都解開了？
Oh! Why are you all undone?
我才幫你穿好，快過來
I just got you done, now come over, here!
寶貝，你惹到斯蒂文不好的一面了， 你本應該站在他看不見的地方
Baby, you got Steven his bad side, when you need to be on his blind side.
你剛才說你不認識他？
You said you ain't know him?
啊？
Huh?
我說...你剛才說你不認識他
I said… you said you ain't know him.
我不認識
I don't.
你認識
Yes you do.
斯蒂文先生...
Mister Steven…
我不認識
I don't.
你幹嘛朝我撒謊？
Why is you lyin' to me?
我沒有
I ain't.
那你哭什麼？
Then why is you cry?
你嚇到我了
You scarin' me.
我怎麼就嚇到你了？
Why is I'm scarin' you?
因為你很嚇人
Because you scary.
今天下午能和希爾蒂用德語交談， 真是完完全全滋潤了我的靈魂啊
.. to speak German this afternoon with Hildi, was positively soul enriching.
好好在椅子上給我坐著
You stay in that chair.
你之前也提到你很樂意 希爾蒂參與到這次生意
You indicated earlier you'd be willing to part with Hildi.
是啊，當然
Oh yes. Yesiree Bob I did.
這樣的話...我想... 我還有個提議
In that case… allow me… to propose another proposition.
我聽著呢
I'm all ears.
快點，該死！
Hurry up, goddammit!
- 坎迪先生... - 斯蒂文！
Monsieur Candie- – Steven!
你剛才打斷了舒爾茲醫生說話了！
You just interrupted Dr. Schultz here!
嗯...對不起，醫生， 我耳朵已經不大好使了
Uhm… sorry doctor Schultz, my ears ain't worth a damn these days.
坎迪先生，我能跟你到廚房說句話嗎
Monsieur Candie, could I get a word with you in the kitchen.
你是讓我從椅子上起來？
You mean get up outta my chair?
如果你能行的話
If you could manage it.
幹嘛？
Why?
是關於甜點的
It's about dessert.
甜點怎麼了？
What about dessert?
我覺得還是私下談比較好
I'd rather discuss that in private.
我們要吃白奶油蛋糕
We're havin' white cake.
這道菜還能弄出什麼驚天動地的花樣啊？
What sort of melodrama could be brewing back there?
你是對的，坎迪先生，我自己解決就好
You right Monsieur Candy, you right, I'll handle it myself.
我們在圖書室見
Meet me in the library.
我就是不懂你今晚怎麼就不願跟我說話
I just can't understand why you won't come talk to the evening,
她在這堶J來你竟然還怪我
she get fucked up 'round here, you blame me.
好，好吧斯蒂文，我...
Fine, fine friend Steven, I…
馬上就過去
will be along momentarily.
是
Yessir.
好吧…
Well…
先生們…
gentlemen…
你也看得出，廚房堻o幫人還是挺有天分的啊
as you can see, talented as they are no doubt in the kitchen,
但時不時的... 還是需要大人來指點一下
from time to time… adult supervision is required.
失陪一會兒
If you'll excuse me a moment.
你們可以開始換餐具了
You may clear the dinner service.
動作快點
Hurry up girl.
舒爾茲醫生...
So Dr. Schultz…
給我們講個馬戲團的故事怎樣？
Why don't you regal us with the tale of the circus?
馬戲團啊！
The circus!
怎麼回事？
What is the matter?
這群小兔崽子不是來買什麼打手的
Them motherfuckers ain't here to buy no mandingos.
他們想要那個女的
They wants that girl.
斯蒂文，你在說什麼呢？
Steven, what the hell are you talkin' about, hm?
他們把你當猴耍呢，我說的是這個
They playin' your ass for a fool, that what I'm talkin' bout.
他們來這堨i不是買什麼壯漢的
They ain't here for no muscle bound jimmie,
是來買那個女孩的
they here for that girl.
什麼...什麼女孩？ 希爾蒂？
What… what girl. What… Hildi?
是啊，希爾蒂，她和姜戈？
Yeah, Hildi. Her and Django?
這兩個人以前就認識
Them niggers know each other.
他.. 他剛剛才買下愛斯基摩人喬啊
He… he just bought Eskimo Joe.
他給你錢了沒？
Did he give you any money?
不，還沒有，但他們...
No, not yet, but they go-
那他什麼都還沒買吧，目前來說
Then he didn't buy diddly, not yet no how.
但他剛剛要開口說買真正想買的人， 我正好打斷了
But he's just about to buy who he come here to buy, when I interrupted him.
謝謝你斯蒂文， 不客氣卡爾文
Thank you Steven. You're welcome Calvin.
你...你什麼時候發現的？
Whe- where you gettin' all this?
他們幹嘛繞這麼大一圈為了一個黑人...
Why would they go through all that trouble for a nigger with a-
背後被打得一塌糊塗的， 甚至都不值三百塊？
with a chewed up back, ain't worth three hundred dollars?
他們這樣是因為姜戈愛著希爾蒂
They're doin' it cause that nigger Django's in love with Hildi.
她很有可能是他的老婆
She probably his wife.
那那個德國人管那個狗娘養的黑人 愛著誰幹嘛啊
Now, why that German give a fuck who that uppity son-of-a-bitch is in love with,
我只能說我不知道
I'm sure I don't know.
如果她才是他們的目標...
If she's who they want…
為什麼這... 這整件曼丁戈的事是幹嘛？
why this whole… snake oil pitch about mandingos in?
你平時是不會隨便就扔掉三百塊錢的吧
You wouldn't pay no never mind into three hundred dollar.
但有這一萬二的生意呢？
But that twelve thousand?
這讓你特友好了是吧
That made you real friendly now, didn'it?
的確
Yes it did.
他老婆，啊？
His wife, uh?
如果有蛇的話…
If it had been a snake…
我們已經弄死他們了
we would have beat'em.
這些騙人的…該死的時代…
Those lyin'… goddamn time…
狗娘養的，浪費我時間
wastin' sonsabitches.
狗雜種們!
Sonsabitches!
...離開了新奧爾良，我有了很多... 舞台經驗
.. out of New Orleans, so I had quite a bit of practice with… theaters types.
哦你在這呢
Oh there you are!
我還在想你是不是和那個老傢伙私奔了
I was beginning to think that you and that old crow ran off together.
要那樣就成大新聞了，是吧？
That'd be a hell of a note, wouldn't it?
勞拉...
Lara Lee…
我剛才看到窗外
I was just lookin' out the big window.
比利·可拉什正在
Billy Crash is out there dealin' with some
跟一個狡猾的奴隸商交涉， 那人想賣幾頭馬駒
shady slaver try n' sellin' a passel of ponys,
親愛的你能不能出去派幾個人，幫我盯著點
would you be a dear and go out there give them gals an eyeball.
- 當然了，弟弟 - 謝謝你親愛的
– Of course, brother. – Thank you, darling.
好吧，生意是談不完的
Okay. Business never sleeps.
有個提議...
A propos…
你進來之前，我們還在討論 我能不能買下布隆希達
before your exit, we were discussing the possibility of my purchasing Broomhilda.
啊，我們會談的
Ah yes! Yes we would.
會談的，過一會兒
And we will again… in a moment.
這位朋友是誰啊？
Who is your little friend?
這是本...
This is Ben…
他曾經是家僕 在這邊生活過很長時間的
He's a Ol'Joe that… lived around here for a long time.
我是說，真的很久
And I do mean a long damn time.
當老本在這...
Well Ben here…
照顧我的父親...
took care of my daddy…
和我父親的父親...
and my daddy's daddy…
直到後來有一天...
till the open kill doe who one day…
他也開始照料我
who been took care o'me.
在這樣一個密西西比州的 大農場主家長大
Growin'up the son of a… of a huge plantation owner in Mississippi
我這樣一個白人，跟所有的黑奴共事
puts a white men in contact with a whole lot o'… black faces.
我這輩子都在這堳袡L... 就在這，坎迪園
I spent my whole life here… right here… in Candyland…
周圍都是...黑人
surrounded… by black faces.
每天都能見到他們，出門回家都看見
And seein' them ev'ry day, day in day out, I…
我只有一個問題啊
I only had one question.
他們幹嘛不殺了我們呢？
Why don't they kill us?
就在那邊那個門廊...
Now right up there on that porch…
五十年來，每週三次，
three times a week for fifty years,
這位本...會用刮鬍刀給我父親刮臉
Ol'Ben here… would shave my Daddy with a straight razor.
現在呢...如果我是老本， 我會一刀把我父親的喉嚨割了
Now… if I was Ol'Ben, I would have cut my Daddy's goddamn throat,
而且我完全不會等個50年再動手
and it wouldn't have taken me no fifty years to do it neither.
但他從未這麼做
But he never did.
為什麼呢？
Why not?
你們看...
You see…
「類比」這個手法的掌握…
the science of analogy…
關鍵就是要準確理解兩種事物的區別
is crucial to understandin' the… separation about two species.
這個黑人的頭骨呢…
In the skull of the African here…
負責「順從」的這部分區域
the area associated with submissiveness
比地球上其他人， 或者說其他種族的人都要大
is larger than any human or any other sup human species on planet earth.
如果檢查一下…
If you examine…
這堻o片頭骨…
this peace of skull here…
你會看到有三個不同的凹陷
you'll notice three distinct dimples.
這...這...還有這
Here… here… and here.
現在...
Now…
如果我手堛瑰Y骨 是牛頓或者伽利略的
If I was holding a skull of a- of a… of an Isaac Newton or Galileo,
這三個凹陷會發現存在於頭骨的...
these three dimples would be found in the area o'the skull most associated with…
負責創造性的部位
creativity.
但這個頭骨是老本的
Βut th??' th? ?kull ?f Οl'Β?n.
在老本的這個頭骨堜O，由基因決定
And in the skull of Ol'Ben, unburden by genes,
這三個凹陷所在的區域是...
these three dimples exist in the area of the skull most associated with…
負責奴性的
servility.
在座這位聰明人...
Now Bright Boy…
我承認你非常聰明
I will admit you are pretty clever.
但如果我用手上這把錘子
But if I took this hammer here…
敲碎你的頭骨...
and I bashed it in your skull…
你頭骨上這三個凹陷窩...
you would have the same three dimples….
會在同樣的地方
in the same place…
跟老本一樣
as Ol'Ben.
把你們的手全部平攤在桌面上！
Now lay your palms flat on the table top!
你們膽敢把手離開這鱉甲材質的桌面
If you lift those palms off that turtle shell table top,
布奇會把你們兩個全部打得腦袋開花！
Mr. Butch is gonna let loose with both barrels of that sawed off!
今晚這晚飯過程中扯謊的人太多了
There have been a latta lies said around this diner table here tonight,
但這句話你最好還是相信！
but that you can believe!
摩吉先生
Mr. Moguy,
能不能勞駕你把這兩位褲兜堛犖j拿走？
would you be so kind as to collect the pistol hangin' on those boys hips here?
非常感謝
Thank you ever so much.
醫生
Doctor.
剛才我們說到哪了
Where were we?
混球
Jackass.
哦對了
Oh yes…
我想你剛才正準備 跟我提議要買下布隆希達吧
I do believe you were just getting ready to make me a proposition to buy Broomhilda.
我沒說錯吧？
I am right?
沒錯
Right then.
把希爾蒂帶出來！
Bring out Hildi!
這邊走
Your way, honey.
跟我好好的在椅子上坐著！
Sit your ass in that goddamn chair!
把手放在桌面上
Lay your hands flat on that table.
給我閉嘴！
And shut your mouth!
舒爾茲醫生...在格林威爾， 你自己也說了，
Dr. Schultz… in Greenville, you yourself said,
為了那個「對的黑奴」
that for the “Right Nigger” you'd be willing to pay
你很樂意考慮付天價
what some may consider is a ridiculous amount.
我當時說，「你說的天價是多少？」
To which, me myself said, “What is your definition of ridiculous?”,
你說，「一萬二」。
to which you said, “Twelve thousand dollars”.
現在考慮到你們走了這麼遠的路
Now considering you all have ridden a whole lotta miles,
經歷了這麼多麻煩事
went to a whole lotta trouble,
還浪費了這麼多口水 來買這位漂亮的女士
and done spread a whole lotta bull, to purchase this lovely lady right here,
那其實布隆希達才是真正的 「對的黑奴」吧！
it would appear that Broomhilda is in fact the “Right Nigger”!
如果你們想帶著布隆希達離開坎迪園...
And if y'all wanna leave Candyland with Broomhilda…
價錢還是一萬二
the price is twelve thousand dollars.
我想，你應該是遵循「買就買不買就滾」 的買賣方式吧
And I take it you prefer the “take it or leave it” style of negotiating?
的確，醫生
Yes I do, doctor.
你也知道，芝卡索縣的法律規定， 布隆希達屬於我的個人財產
You see, under the laws of Chickasaw County, Broomhilda here is my property.
對我自己的財產，我想幹嘛就幹嘛！
And I can chose to do with my property whatever I so desire!
你要是覺得我給這黑人開價太高
And if you all think my price for this nigger here is too steep,
那我的打算就是...
what I'm gonna desire to do is…
抄起我的錘子，活活砸死她！
take this fuckin' hammer here, and beat her ass to death with it!
就在你們倆面前！
Right in front of both y'all!
不錯吧，夥計們？
Ain't it good, fella?
然後我們就可以檢查檢查 布隆希達腦殼上的三個洞在哪了！
Then we can examine the three dimples inside Broomhilda skull!
現在！
Now!
你買還是不買呢，醫生？啊？
What's it gonna be, Doc? Huh?
買還是不買？
What's it gonna be?
我能不能把手拿起來一會兒 取身上的錢包？
May I lift the hands off the table top in order to remove my billfold?
請吧
Yes you may.
這是一萬二
That twelve.
成交！
Sold!
賣給這位可愛優秀的大鬍子， 以及他不怎麼優秀的黑鬼
To the man with the exceptional beard, and his unexceptional nigger.
- 摩吉先生 - 是的卡爾文？
Mr. Moguy. – Yes Calvin?
你給這位先生出個一萬二的收據吧
You make this gentleman a receipt for twelve thousand dollar, please.
- 一萬二啊 - 嗯
– Twelve thousand dollar. – Hm.
跟你們做生意真是太愉快了
It was a pleasure doin' business with ya all.
先生們...
Now gentlemen…
你們可以跟我一起來客廳
If you care to join me in the parlor…
我們還有蛋糕要吃
we will be serving white cake.
幹得漂亮，卡爾文
Well done, Calvin.
對不起...對不起，女士？
Excuse me… Excuse me, madam?
能不能不要彈貝多芬了？
Could you please stop playing Beethoven?
放開這豎琴！
Take your hands off that harp!
醫生！
Doctor!
- 醫生，你不能進那個房間！ - 嘿，斯蒂文
– Doc, you can't go in there! – Hey uh, Steven, hey!
- 他又沒什麼事要去那 - 讓他去吧
– He got no business goin' in there. – Let it be.
他只是有點不開心嘛，我來搞定
He's a little upset, that's all. I'll handle this.
白奶油蛋糕要不要？
White cake?
我不吃甜的，謝謝
I don't go in for sweets, thank you.
你還在為剛才的生意憂愁呢
You brooding 'bout me getting the best of ya, uh?
其實我剛才在想 你今天拿去餵狗的那個可憐人
Actually, I was thinking of that poor devil you fed to the dogs today.
達達尼昂
D'Artagnan.
我就想，大仲馬會怎麼看這件事
And I was wondering what Dumas would make of all this.
誰？
Come again?
亞歷山大·仲馬， 寫了《三個火槍手》的
Alexandre Dumas. He wrote “The Three Musketeers”.
哦是他啊
Yes of course, doctor.
我想你應該是他書迷
I figured you must be an admirer,
你的奴隸都是用書主角的名字命名
you named your slave after his novel's lead character.
如果大仲馬今天也在場
Now if Alexandre Dumas had been there today,
我在想他會怎麼看？
I wonder what he would have made of it?
你在懷疑他不會同意？
You doubt he'd approve?
是，他如果會同意，才令人起疑
Yes, his approval would be a dubious proposition at best.
法國人的心腸軟？
Soft hearted Frenchy?
大仲馬是黑人
Alexandre Dumas is black.
那些是布隆希達的文件嗎？
Are these Broomhilda's papers?
- 是的 - 我能看看嗎？
– Yes they are. – May I?
- 當然 - 謝謝
– Of course! – Thank you.
這份買賣文書當然也是 直接有還她自由身的效力的，醫生
I dealt- her bill of sale of ownership is written of course a freedom papers, doctor.
請問你有筆嗎？
Would you have ink and pen for me?
在那邊小桌子上
Right over there, on that little table.
謝謝
Thank you.
布隆希達·范·夏夫特...
Broomhilda Von Shaft…
你現在自由了
consider yourself a free woman.
坎迪先生…
Mister Candy…
一般情況下我會說「再見了」，
Normally, I would say “auf wiedersehen”.
但「再見了」意思是說要再見面，
But since what “auf wiedersehen” actually means is “till I see you again”,
然後我的確不想再跟你見面了
and since I never wish to see you again, to you sir,
所以還是說「拜拜」吧
I say good bye.
我們走
Let's go.
走吧
Com'on.
等一等，醫生！
One more moment, Doctor!
嗯？
What?
這是南方的一個傳統
It's a custom here in the South,
一樁生意做完以後
once a business deal is concluded that the two parties…
雙方握手
shake hands.
代表著誠意
It implies good faith.
- 我又不是南方人 - 但是你...
– I'm not from the South. – But you are…
現在在我家呢
in my house doctor….
所以恐怕我要堅持這麼做了
so I'm afraid I must insist.
堅持？堅持什麼？讓我跟你握手？
Insist? On what? That I shake your hand?
哦那不好意思那我只能 堅持跟你相反的想法了
Oh, then I'm afraid I must insist in the opposite direction.
你覺得我怎麼看你的？
You know what I think you are?
你怎麼看我？不，不清楚
What you think I am? No I don't.
我覺得是個輸不起的傢伙
I think you are a bad loser.
我覺得你是個狂妄自大的贏家
And I think you're an abysmal winner.
是這樣…
Never the less…
在芝卡索縣，生意如此還不算做完
here in Chickasaw County, a deal ain't done
除非雙方最終握手
until the two parties have shook hands.
就算文書都簽了，那也不算數
Even after all that paper signin', don't mean shit…
如果你不跟我握手
you don't shake my hand.
如果我不跟你握手
If I don't shake your hand,
你就扔了那一萬二？
you're gonna throw away twelve thousand dollars?
我看不會吧
I don't think so.
布奇先生
Mr. Butch,
如果這個黑鬼愛好者德國佬不跟我握手 她就想離開這
if she tries to leave here before this nigger lovin' German shakes my hand,
把她打開花
you cut her ass down.
你真想我跟你握手？
You really want me to shake your hand?
我堅持
I insist.
如果真堅持的話
If you insist.
啊卡爾文！
Aaah Calvin!
卡爾文！
Caalvin!
對不起，我實在受不了了
I'm sorry. I couldn't resist.
這個黑鬼瘋了，該死...
The nigger's going crazy, the hell-
救命啊，他對每個人都開槍，啊！
Help, he's blowing everybody- Aaah!
該死！狗娘養的！
Shit! Son of a bitch!
去抓住他
Get that fuckin'…
Get that fuckin'-
該死的狗娘養的，操... 怎麼回事...該死！
Damn sonofabitch, what- what did the fuckin'- goddammit!
我操...
What the-
不要打我啊！
Don't strike me!
蠢材！
You stupid sonofabitch!
抱歉啊傑西！
Sorry Jessie!
誰他媽的給槍給這黑鬼的！
Who the fuck gave a nigger a goddamn gun!
黑鬼，來殺我啊
Nigger, com'on and kill-
啊！天哪！啊！
Aah! God! Ah my God, aah!
狗崽子！
Motherfucker!
停火！
Hold your fire!
不要打了，該死！
Stop shooting, goddammit!
姜戈！
Django!
什麼？
What?
你女人在我們手上！
We got your woman!
比利現在正拿著槍指著她腦袋！
Billy Crash here ha' got his pistol upside her hair!
你停止繼續抵抗，
You'll stop all that gettin'on,
他就不會把她腦袋打開花
he don't blow her goddamn brains out.
我們不是騙你的！
And that ain't no third holes, boy!
我保證
That there is a promise.
哦！
Oh oh!
你還不投降？
You ain't give up?
還想著逃走？
Thought you going, uh?
我們會殺了你的！
We will kill you!
說什麼？！
How shit?!
老實說，別做那嘗試了，姜戈 我對天發誓
Honest, ain't lyin', Django, I swear o' all God.
你投降了？
You give up?
沒人會傷害你的
Ain't no harm gonna come t'you.
我現在還得相信你了？
And I'm supposed to believe your black ass?
對我來說，我才不管你信什麼不信什麼
Personal, I ain't give a good goddamn what you believe or don't believe!
我是覺得，如果你十秒鐘之內不投降
I believe, if you don't give up in the next ten seconds,
我們會把這婊子打到腦袋開花！ 信不信吧！
we gonna blow this bitch her brains out! Believe that!
信不信吧！
Believe that!
放棄我好了
You give me up.
六！
Six!
讓我去吧！
Just let me go!
七！
Seven!
- 我愛你太深 - 姜戈
– I take care too much. – Django.
八！
Eight!
我愛你
I love you.
九！
Nine!
- 等等！ - 不！
– Hold it! – No!
我投降
I give up.
我聽不清啊，黑鬼
I can't hear you, nigger.
我說，我投降！
I said: I give up!
吊著還舒服吧，黑鬼
Hock a litl'e doodle, nigger.
聽說你是個賞金獵手啊？
So y'all bounty hunters, huh?
傳言還挺血腥的
I knew there was something fishy 'bout y'all.
我們找到了你的「通緝令」傳單， 馬鞍的袋子媮晹釩雃h畫像
We found your “wanted” posters… and book of figures in your saddle bags.
我得說...
I gotta say…
我以前還從沒聽說過有黑人賞金獵手呢
I ain't never heard of no black bounty hunter before.
黑人收錢殺白人啊，這工作感覺怎麼樣？
A black boy paid to kill white men, how d'you like that line of work?
做著感覺肯定很爽吧？
Prob'bly pretty good while it lasted, uh?
是時候跟你的蛋蛋說拜拜了，黑鬼
Time to say goodnight to them nuts, black.
數到三
On three…
一…
One…
我來
I got you.
二…
Two…
冷靜點黑鬼，冷靜
Calm down nigger, keep calm.
老大？
Cap't?
勞拉小姐在找你
Miss Lara wants to see you.
是跟葬禮有關的
That is somethin' to do with the Old Man's funeral.
哦，還有她不想閹掉姜戈了
Oh, and she changed her mind 'bout snippin' Django.
她要把他送去拉奎·迪基一家
She gonna give 'em to the LeQuint Dickey people.
那她怎麼沒跟我說啊
Well she didn't waste a minute tellin' me.
真掃興
How disappointing.
你和我
You n' me.
這些不是…
These ain't…
你帶來的東西
what you take with you.
大宅堬{在所有的人
Your black ass been all the motherfuckers' in that Big House
過去幾個小時全都在討論你
could talk about for the last few hours.
這些白人永遠也想不出個好點子
Seemed like white folk ain't never had a bright idea in their life,
要怎樣才能好好宰了你
was comin' up with all kinds o'ways to kill your ass.
不得不說的是，他們大多數 都打著你蛋蛋的主意
Now mind ya, most of 'dem ideas had to do with fuckin' with your fun parts.
這或許是個好主意，但其實...
Now, that may seem like a good idea, but truth is…
把蛋割了以後呢，大多數人都會流血死掉...
when you snip a nigger's nuts, most of 'em bleed out, know 'bout…
大多數人七分鐘就死了吧
seven minutes, most of 'em…
最多就是這樣
More than most.
然後我就說...
Then I say is…
該死的...
Hells bells…
我們賣去拉奎·迪基那邊的黑鬼 下場慘得多呢
the niggers we sell to LeQuint Dickey, got it worse then that.
他們還在嚷嚷「我們用鞭子抽死他」
And they're still sayin' “Let's whip 'em to death”,
「讓他去打曼丁戈」「讓斯通瑟的狗咬死他」
“Dump 'em to the mandingos”, “Feed 'em to Stonesipher's dogs”.
我說「這有什麼很特別的？我們不是一直這樣嗎！」
And I say, “What's so special 'bout that? We do that shit all the time!
該死的，我們送去拉奎·迪基那堛熄簞 死得要慘得多啊
Hells bells, the niggers we sell to LeQuint Dickey got it worse then that”.
誰知道就在這時， 勞拉小姐就有了這麼個想法
Low and behold, out of nowhere, miss Lara come up with the bright idea
要把你送去拉奎·迪基採礦公司
of givin' your ass to the LeQuint Dickey Mining Company.
作為他們採礦公司的奴隸，
And as a slave of the LeQuint Dickey Mining Company,
我要說，直到你死掉的那天，
hence forth, till the day you die,
每天，從早到晚
all day, ev'ryday,
你會舉著大錘
you will be swingin' a sledgehammer,
把大石頭敲成小石頭
turning big rocks into little rocks.
等你到了那堙A你會被剝奪姓名
Now when you get there, they gonna take away your name,
只有個編號，還有個錘子
give you a number, and a sledgehammer,
告訴你「去幹活」
and say “get to work”.
多說半個字，舌頭就沒了
One word of says, they cuts out your tongue,
他們也挺擅長做那個的，很難相信吧
they's good at that too, you won't believe that.
他們也是為了你好啊
Ooh, they does that for you.
他們會讓你沒日沒夜地做工， 直到你站不起來
They gonna work you, all day, ev'ry day, till your back give up.
到那時他們就用錘子把你腦袋敲開花
Then they gonna hit you in the head with the hammer,
丟到黑奴的萬人坑堨h
tow your ass down the nigger hole.
那...就會是你的結局，姜戈
And that… will be the story end for you, Django.
去拉奎·迪基採礦公司的路上
嘿，白人小哥
Hey, white boy…
我說，嘿，白人小哥！
I said: hey, white boy!
閉嘴，黑鬼，你沒有什麼話是我想聽的
Shut up, black, you ain't got nothing to say I wanna hear.
你想不想掙個一萬一千塊？
How'd you like to make eleven thousand dollars?
我沒聽清？
D'you ain't hear?
我說，你想不想去掙一萬一千塊啊
I said, how d'you like to make eleven thousand dollars?
一萬一千五，具體說的話
Eleven thousand five hundred, actually.
你說什麼呢？
What the fuck are you talking about?
在那邊坎迪園農場
Back there at that plantation Candyland,
有一份一萬一千五的財產
there was an eleven thousand five hundred dollar fortune,
就在那坐著，你就這樣經過了
just sittin' there, and y'all rode right past it.
你真是該死啊黑鬼，我們可不是強盜
You be damned, blackie, we're not bandits.
我還沒說呢，這財寶最好的一點就是呢
I ain't sayin' that, nice thing 'bout this fortune it is.
不是什麼違法的事，你不用偷的
It ain't illegal, you can't steal it,
是去贏回來的，小哥
ya gotta earn it, white boy.
有什麼話就直說
You got something to say, mate, you say it.
坎迪園那一萬一千五的財產
The eleven thousand five hundred dollar fortune waiting for you back at Candyland,
就是不管死活都要捉拿的一份賞金
is in the form of a wanted dead or alive bounty
懸賞史密蒂·巴考爾和他的團伙的
on Smitty Bacall, and the Bacall Gang.
史密蒂·巴考爾誰啊？
Who the fuck is Smitty Bacall?
史密蒂·巴考爾是這個馬車劫匪團伙的頭目
Smitty Bacall is the leader of this murdering gang of stagecoach robbers,
巴考爾黑幫
the Bacall Gang.
他的腦袋值七千塊，不管死活
There's a seven thousand dollar wanted dead or alive bounty on him,
他手下每個人腦袋也值一千五
one thousand five hundred dollars for each of his three accomplices.
丹迪·邁克爾斯
Dandy Michaels,
傑拉德·納什
Gerald Nash,
還有瘋子克雷格·科恩斯
Crazy Craig Koons.
這四個人現在都在坎迪園
Now all four o'them gentlemen, they're back there at Candyland,
哈哈大笑呢，你知道為什麼嗎？
laughin' their ass off. You know why?
因為他們剛剛才保住小命
Cause they just got away with murder.
但事情不必如此發展
But it ain't got to be that way.
你和你的夥計們，就可以拿到這個錢了
You and your mate, young rabbit and Yango get that money.
這些人幹嘛了來著？
What these jokers do again?
這些狗娘養的，他們... 他們濫殺無辜
These sonofabitch, they- they killed innocent people.
搶劫馬車，殺了無辜的白人
Stagecoach robbery. Innocent white people!
我口袋埵雀Ё獢A如果你能讓我拿出來
I got the handbill right here in my pocket if you let me get it.
給我
Get it here.
通緝令，死活皆可... 史密蒂·巴考爾和他的團伙
Wanted dead or alive… Smitty Bacall and the Smitty Bacall gang.
但你是個奴隸吧！
But you're a slave!
我才不是什麼奴隸！
I ain't no goddamn slave!
我聽上去像是奴隸嗎？
Do I sound like a fuckin' slave?
- 懸賞七千塊... - 好大一筆錢啊
- 7000 dollars for Smitty Bacall… – This is a shit load!
我是賞金獵手
I'm a bounty hunter.
昨天，我還是自由人，我去了坎迪園
Yesterday, as a free man, I rode in the Candyland,
騎著馬，跟我的德國白人同夥一起， 叫金·舒爾茲，是醫生
on a horse, with my German white partner, Dr. King Schultz.
我們一直從德州就追蹤巴考爾團伙 來到芝卡索縣
We tracked the Bacall gang all the way from Texas, to Chikasaw County.
終於發現他們在坎迪園躲著
We finally found their ass laying low at Candyland.
我們進去抓他們，但事情沒控制住
We went in there to get 'em, things went sour,
我的同夥被殺了，卡爾文·坎迪也中槍了
my partner got killed, Calvin Candie got shot.
所以堶悸漱H都怪到我頭上， 於是我就在這了
Then ev'rybody there decided to blame me, so here I am.
但姜戈可不是什麼奴隸
But Django ain't on that manifest,
你們也知道我不該在這
and all o'you know I ain't supposed to be on this trip.
但那四個人還在那堙A仍舊是通緝犯
But them four men are still back there, they're still wanted,
那一萬一千五還等著人領
and that eleven thousand five hundred is up for grabs,
他們最不希望看到的就是 你們回過頭去找他們
and the last thing they'd expect is y'all ridin' back and gittin' it.
你想說什麼？
What's the deal?
你告訴我們他們的身份... 然後我們給你鬆綁？
You tell us who they are and we… turn you lose?
我可沒告訴你們他們的身份
I ain't tellin' who they are.
聽著，你給我一把槍，一匹馬
Look, you give me a pistol, one o'them horses,
還有那一萬一千五里面的五百塊
and five hundred dollars of that eleven thousand five hundred,
我就指出他們給你們看
and I'll point 'em out to you.
這可真是一大筆錢啊
This a real handbill.
但這一大筆錢也不代表 我們可以相信他的大話吧
Ah jus'cause it's a real handbill's doesn't mean that other bunch o'malarky is.
那一個奴隸身上怎麼會有通緝令傳單？
Now why would a slave have a wanted dead or alive handbill in his pocket?
那個黑人昨天是騎著馬去了坎迪園嗎？
Ain't that black ridin' into Candyland yesterday?
好吧…
Alright…
我再問一遍…
I'm gonna ask you again…
你們得想清楚，我不喜歡騙子
I want you to remember I don't like liars.
他是坎迪園的奴隸嗎， 還是昨天跟著一個白人騎馬進去的？
Is he a Candyland slave, or did he ride in with a white man on horse yesterday?
是啊
Yeah.
他們帶我們從格林威爾拍賣會過來
They walked us from the Greenville Auction and
他和一個白人一起騎馬的
he rode in on a horse with a white man.
那這個白人…
And this white man…
這黑人是他奴隸？
was the black his slave?
他才不是奴隸
He weren't no slave.
你們...你們肯定？
You- you fuckin' sure about that?
非常肯定
Damn sure.
坎迪園都發生了什麼？
What happened over at Candyland?
各種槍戰…
Bunch of shootin'…
主人被槍擊
master got shot.
- 誰打的？ - 那個德國人
– Who shot 'em? – The German.
他幹嘛殺他？
Why did he do that?
這黑人還有那德國人假裝自己是買奴隸的， 但他們不是
The nigger and the German was actin' like they were slavers, but they weren't.
那他們是什麼人？
Well, what were they?
賞金獵手
Bounty hunters.
我操，羅伊，我覺得... 這可是大事啊！
Fuck me Roy, I mean this- this could be big, mate!
好吧黑哥兒們
Well, smoke…
成交
you gotta deal.
我還有個條件
I got one more condition.
什麼？
What is that?
我們到了以後...到了要殺人時候
When we get there… when the time come…
讓我幫忙一起殺
you let me help you kill 'em.
你還挺逗樂嘛！
You're a funny bugger!
- 給他鬆綁 - 好，好
– Get him loose. – Yeah, yeah.
我們一言為定了，黑哥
You got yourself a deal, blackie.
我們一言為定
You got yourself a deal, mate.
- 帶個黑哥兒們一起沒問題吧！ - 沒問題
– You alright for a black fella! – Oh yeah!
天哪…
Jeez…
好了...鬆綁了，老兄
There ya go… There ya go, mate.
我們給你那個背貨的馬
For you, we'll give you that pack horse over here.
馬鞍上都背了什麼？
What's them saddle bags got in?
炸藥
Dynamite.
我可不要騎有背著炸藥的馬
I ain't ridin' no horse with no goddamn dynamite on his back.
可以理解
I can understand that.
弗蘭基，把炸藥拿下來， 放到黑鬼的籠子堨h
Frankie, we take 'em sticks off that horse, and stick 'em in the nigger cage.
你們有炸藥可以玩咯！
A little dynamite for you black ass to play with!
弗洛伊德，你拿著馬車上那把獵槍的是吧？
Hey Floyd, you got that rifle on the wagon, don't you?
沒錯
Yeah, alright.
不用把你的槍和槍帶給他了
Don't you give 'em your gun and gun belt.
好了，拿好了別掉了
Now, don't drop the fucking thing, alright?
我才修好準星，現在很好用
I just had the sights fixed, and that perfect.
啊，多謝告知
Uh, that's good to know.
把炸藥給我
Throw me up that dynamite.
- 傑克？ - 嗯？
– Jake! – Yeah?
你得出去看看那該死的狗是怎麼了！
You gotta try to see what's goin'on with that goddamn dog!
下地獄吧，狗崽子們！
Go to hell, you motherfucker!
我也愛你
Love you too, son.
是我，寶貝
It's me, baby.
#在甜蜜的
?In the sweet…
#告別聲中
?byin' bye…
#我們會留下
?we will leave…
#這首動人的歌
?on that beautiful song.
#再見...再見...
?Byin' bye… bye bye…
#我們會留下...一句再見
?we will leave… we will leave byin' bye.
科拉
Cora,
能給我們煮點咖啡嗎？
would you prepare us some coffee?
西芭，你去幫忙
Sheba, you help her.
來吧
Come on.
#在甜蜜的
?In the sweet…
#告別聲中
– ?byin' bye, ooh…
你們會和卡爾文一起的說再見的
Ya'all gonna be together with Calvin and the byin bye.
不過要比你們想像的快一點啊
Just a bit sooner than ya'all was expectin'.
比利·可拉什！
Billy Crash!
你幹嘛要…?
Now why would…?
哦對了
Oh, that's right.
我們上次見面的時候， 你的手放在我的...
Last time I seen you, you had your hands on my…
姜戈！
Django!
你怎麼回來了，狗娘養的！
You back, sonofabitch!
這是給她親愛的比利的
To dear son, hey Billy.
噢不！
Oh no!
現在各位黑人，我建議你們離這些白人遠點
Now, all o'you black folks, I suggest you get away from all these white folks.
沒說你，斯蒂文
Not you Steven.
你給我原地好好站著
You're right where you belong.
科拉，你走之前…
Uh, Cora, before you go…
跟勞拉小姐道個別吧？
would you tell miss Lara goodbye?
干...幹嘛？
Do- do what now?
我說...跟勞拉小姐...道別
I said tell… miss Lara… goodbye.
再見了勞拉小姐
Bye miss Lara.
你們倆現在走吧
Ya'all two run along now.
斯蒂文！
Steve!
你覺得...我的新衣服怎麼樣？
How you like my… new dirt?
一小時之前我還不知道 勃艮第的顏色適合我呢
You know for an hour, I didn't know the burgundy was my color.
我數過你開了六槍了，黑鬼
I count six shots, nigger.
我帶了兩把槍，黑鬼
I count two guns, nigger.
你說在這農場的76年堙A 你見過任何種類的折磨是吧？
You said in 76 years on this plantation, you seen all o'manner shit done, ain'it?
但我也注意到…
But I noticed…
你的膝蓋骨不大好使啊
you didn't knit your knee cap.
76年啊，斯蒂文
Seventy six years, Steven…
來來往往的黑奴你見過多少個，七千？
how many niggers you think you see come n' go, uh, 7000…?
八千？
8000…?
九千？
9000…?
9999?
卡爾文·坎迪嘴埵R出每個字的都是狗屁
Ev'ry single word that came out of Calvin Candy's mouth was nothin' but cold shit.
但他有件事是說對了
But he was right 'bout one thing.
我就是那萬分之一
I am that one nigger in ten thousand.
你這狗崽子！
You sonofabitch!
操你媽！
You motherfucker!
哦上帝啊，讓我殺了這個黑鬼吧！
Oh please Jesus, let me kill this nigger!
你不會就此逃脫的，姜戈
You ain't go get away with this, Django.
他們會一直追著你
They go n' catch your black ass…
你出門得小心了，黑鬼
You gonna be holdin' out o'a pole just now, nigger,
賞金獵手現在要抓的是你
the bounty hunters gonna be looking for you.
你可以跑
You can run, nigger,
但他們會找到你的！
but they gonna find your ass!
等找到以後， 他們對你做什麼就說不准了
And when they do, oh I love what they gonna do to your ass.
會把你一槍打死的
They gonna just kill you, nigger!
你完了！
You the fucked up!
這個坎迪園，黑鬼！
This Candyland, nigger!
你不能毀了坎迪園！
You can't destroy Candyland!
我們一直生活在這堙A你不能打敗坎迪園
We been here long way, you can't beat Candyland.
一個黑人不能平白無故就這麼冒出來...
Can't no nigger gunfighter get all the way from don't know where to…
姜戈！
Django!
你這狗娘養的...
You up on a sonofab-
嘿小搗蛋鬼
Hey Little Trouble Maker.
嘿大搗蛋鬼
Hey Big Trouble Maker.
你知道他們會怎麼叫你嗎？
You know what they are going to call you?
南方最快的快槍手
The Fastest Gun in the South.
我們走吧
Let git outta here.
Caption and sync: jcdr v 1.1 - 08.01.2013
編劇、導演：昆汀·塔倫蒂諾 =翻譯：米粒=
Thanks to Boon23 for his corrections!